2023-03-11 17:43:46 INFO - Scenario 'Font settings: Check of text theme' start 2023-03-11 17:43:46 INFO - Setting application driver using the server on 'https://hub-cloud.browserstack.com/wd/hub' 2023-03-11 17:44:44 INFO - Application on platform 'ANDROID' is ready... 2023-03-11 17:44:44 INFO - Session id - f0dde95515a9b3aab4bb6d53a18255c95b9970b7 2023-03-11 17:44:44 INFO - Step 0 - I add "LYRASIS Reads" account from welcomeScreen 2023-03-11 17:44:44 INFO - Button 'btnCloseTutorial' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:44:48 INFO - Button 'btnFindLibrary' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:44:48 INFO - Button 'Search' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:44:50 INFO - Text Field 'Search' :: Clearing 2023-03-11 17:44:50 INFO - Text Field 'Search' :: Typing 'LYRASIS Reads' 2023-03-11 17:44:52 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:44:52 INFO - Step 1 - Account 'LYRASIS Reads' is present on Accounts screen 2023-03-11 17:44:53 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:44:54 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:44:55 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:44:57 INFO - Step 2 - I enter credentials for 'LYRASIS Reads' account 2023-03-11 17:44:57 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:44:57 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:44:58 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:45:00 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:45:01 INFO - Locking credential with barcode 01230000000306 2023-03-11 17:45:01 INFO - There are books on the account: 2023-03-11 17:45:02 INFO - There is not books on the account. 2023-03-11 17:45:02 INFO - Count of books on the account after opening account: 0 2023-03-11 17:45:02 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Clearing 2023-03-11 17:45:02 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Typing '01230000000306' 2023-03-11 17:45:04 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Clearing 2023-03-11 17:45:04 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Typing '********' 2023-03-11 17:45:06 INFO - Button 'Log in' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:45:13 INFO - Button 'Log ... action' :: Getting text from element 2023-03-11 17:45:13 INFO - Step 3 - Login is performed successfully 2023-03-11 17:45:34 INFO - Button 'Log ... action' :: Getting text from element 2023-03-11 17:45:34 INFO - Step 4 - I open Catalog 2023-03-11 17:45:34 INFO - Button 'tabCatalog' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:45:55 INFO - Step 5 - I open search modal 2023-03-11 17:46:15 INFO - Button 'Search' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:46:17 INFO - Step 6 - I search 'available' book of distributor 'Palace Marketplace' and bookType 'EBOOK' from "LYRASIS Reads" and save as 'bookNameInfo' 2023-03-11 17:46:17 INFO - Count of attempts to get random book name without bad symbols-1 2023-03-11 17:46:17 INFO - randomBookName: The City of Rocks 2023-03-11 17:46:17 INFO - Error details button is not present 2023-03-11 17:46:18 INFO - Text Field 'Search value input' :: Sending keys 'The City of Rocks' 2023-03-11 17:46:20 INFO - Error details button is not present 2023-03-11 17:46:25 INFO - Step 7 - Click GET action button on EBOOK book with 'bookNameInfo' bookName on catalog books screen and save book as 'bookInfo' 2023-03-11 17:46:25 INFO - Label 'lblAuthor' :: Getting text from element 2023-03-11 17:46:25 INFO - Button 'actionButton' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:46:32 INFO - Step 8 - Open EBOOK book with READ action button and 'bookNameInfo' bookName on catalog books screen and save book as 'bookInfo' 2023-03-11 17:46:32 INFO - Label 'lblAuthor' :: Getting text from element 2023-03-11 17:46:33 INFO - Label 'lblBookName' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:46:33 INFO - Step 9 - Click READ action button on book details screen 2023-03-11 17:46:34 INFO - Button 'Read' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:46:34 INFO - Step 10 - I scroll page forward from 7 to 9 times 2023-03-11 17:46:34 INFO - Scrolling 7 times on reader epub screen 2023-03-11 17:46:53 INFO - Step 11 - I open font settings 2023-03-11 17:46:54 INFO - Button 'btnFontSettings' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:46:55 INFO - Step 12 - I change contrast to BLACK_TEXT_ON_WHITE 2023-03-11 17:46:55 INFO - Button 'setThemeLight' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:46:56 INFO - Step 13 - The BLACK_TEXT_ON_WHITE background is correct 2023-03-11 17:46:56 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-03-11 17:46:56 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-03-11 17:46:57 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-03-11 17:46:57 INFO -

Chapter 1

Ten days later, Albuquerque, New Mexico

I JERKED the cell phone away from my ear and looked at it as if it had lost its mind—or its chip. Del Dahlman, a local attorney, wanted me to drop everything and run down to the UNM Emergency Center to interview a man named Richard Martinson. When he told me why, I assumed he was kidding. He had to be.

“You want me to go question a ducknapper? There’s no such thing. He’s just a plain, ordinary chicken thief.”

“Whatever,” Del said. “I need you to catch him before he leaves the emergency room.”

This was simply too good to let go. “Have you called in the FBI yet?”

“Don’t be an ass,” Del snapped.

“Donkeys now? What is this, a menagerie run amok? Who did it? The pigs? Good Lord, it’s Orwell’s Animal Farm come to life.”

“Dammit, Vince, I’m serious. This is serious. I need you to get over there right away.”

I stared at the bright blue sky on this cloudless Saturday afternoon and considered hanging up on Del. I stood on the fourth tee of the golf course at the North Valley Country Club with Paul Barton. Although we lived together, it was a rare occasion when Paul and I could share the daylight hours. Between my confidential investigations business and Paul’s schedule—UNM grad school summer courses and an aquatic director’s job at the country club—we were the proverbial ships passing in the night.

I resented Del’s intrusion, but he and I went back a long way—some of it sweet, some of it bittersweet, and some downright sour.

“You need to get a move on,” he said. “You’ve got to get to him before they let him go. His name’s Richard Martinson, but… but they call him Liver Lips.” Del didn’t like playing the straight man.

“Liver Lips? Calves’ liver or…. No, don’t tell me. Let me guess. Goose liver.”

“You’re wasting my time, BJ.” He always called me Vince, a carryover from the days when we were a couple. Anytime he resorted to addressing me as BJ like the rest of the world, he was pissed.

“Hey, you called me. Right in the middle of my backswing, as a matter of fact.”

“Are you going to do it or not?”

I sighed. One of my better clients, Del commanded my attention. “Okay. Give me the details. There’s really a lawsuit on this thing?”

“No, it’s not actually a suit… yet.”

“Then why is your firm involved? More to the point, why are you involving me?”

He went defensive. “We’re New Mexico counsel for the Greater Southwest Ranchers Insurance Company or GSR, as they liked to be called, and the VP handling their problem and I are old friends. At this point I’m doing this as a favor to him. At any rate, the missing bird’s name is Quacky Quack the Second. This—”

“Quacky what?”

“Shut up, Vince.”

I snickered through the rest of his briefing, hung up, and turned to my golfing companion. Paul got as good a laugh out of it as I had. In fact, we both broke up a couple of times during the retelling.

I DO not like walking into a situation I don’t understand, and I damned well didn’t understand this one. But I had no trouble locating Martinson in the waiting room at the hospital. Liver Lips. The young man’s nickname described him perfectly. His thick, purple-hued oral projections drew my eye like a magnet. Only later did I notice he was skinny, seedy, and carried a generally disreputable air. Gray eyes darted here and there as if he were constantly searching for a bolt-hole. The man’s scalp glistened through thin strands of frizzy blond hair. Whether he was talking or listening or simply idle, his dark tongue periodically snaked out to wash those heavy lips. Seldom had I been so thoroughly repulsed by another’s physical appearance.

He looked at me blankly after I handed over my card and introduced myself. “A private eye, huh. What you want with me?”

“I need to ask you a few questions.” I nodded at the bandages covering his forearms. “What happened?”

“Had a fight with a thorn bush. Frigging bush won.” He went for humor, glancing up through thin, colorless lashes to see if it had worked.

I pointed to the red veins snaking up out of the white bandage on his right arm just short of his elbows. “Thorn bushes didn’t give you that infection. That’s blood poisoning. How’d you get it?”

“Tangled with the wrong bush, I guess. Then didn’t get it treated. Turned bad on me, I guess.”

“Come on, I’ll give you a ride down to my office where we can talk in private.”

“Ain’t got time. Gotta get outta here. I been here six frigging hours.”

“Okay, I’ll call Lt. Eugene Enriquez down at the police department, and we’ll have this talk at APD.”

He blinked rapidly three times. “No cops, man. Don’t need no cops. I ain’t done nothing, so leave me alone.”

“What are you doing up here? You live down in Deming, don’t you?” I drew on the thin biography Del had provided.

“Ain’t no law against a man visiting the city. I guess that’s what they do all that advertising on TV for. You know, to get me to come up here and spend my money.”

“You want to tell me about it?”

“About what?” He seemed genuinely perplexed by my question.

“About stealing a valuable… bird.” If I’d said “duck” I’d have burst out laughing.

“Don’t guess I know what you’re talking about.”

“You do a lot of guessing, Richard. But I don’t think the sheriff of Luna County would have sicced me on you if he was just guessing.”

“Hidalgo,” he blurted.

“What?”

“Sheriff of Hidalgo County.”

“Okay, now that you’ve admitted you know all about the theft, tell me about it.”

“Didn’t admit nothing.”

“You know where the abduction… uh, theft took place. Stop wasting my time. What did you want with a prize duck named….” I stopped, unable to call a bird by that ridiculous name.

“Quacky Quack the Second,” he said. “That’s what old Mud Hen calls her. Ain’t that a hoot?”

“Mud Hen?”

“Millicent Muldren. Everybody calls her Mud Hen.”

“She’s the duck’s owner?”

“Yeah. She’s run the Lazy M Ranch since her old man died.”

“Why’d you steal her duck?”

“Who says I did?”

I improvised. “About everybody in the countryside. Police chief, sheriff, Mrs. Muldren. There’s a warrant out for your arrest. Talk to me, and maybe I can do something about that.”

Old Liver Lips wasn’t as dumb as he looked. Those blood-suffused appendages quivered a couple of times before he squared his thin shoulders. “Ain’t nobody gonna arrest me for nothing, I guess. Who’d press charges on something like that?”

“Well, Mud Hen for one, and the insurance company for another.”

“Insurance company?”

“You didn’t know the owner had insured her property?”

“Shoot, I guess there ain’t no insurance company in the world that’d insure a frigging duck.”

I didn’t know much more than he did, but I couldn’t let up on him now. “Then you’d guess wrong. They’ll insure soap bubbles if you pay the premiums.”

Liver Lips wiggled in his chair, looking distinctly uncomfortable. “Uh… you said something about a warrant?”

Flying totally blind, I had no idea if a warrant existed for this character. In fact, I didn’t even know why he was suspected of the theft. Or how Del found out he’d be at the UNM Emergency Center today.

“Yes, but I can deal with that if you give me what I want.”

“Like what?”

“Like what have you done with Qua… with the duck?” His eyes slid away as he opened his mouth and licked his lips. I held up a hand. “Don’t bother to deny it. You’re caught flat out. Man up and admit it. Where’s the duck?”

“Dunno.” The word came out in a whisper.

“Why not?”

“Somebody took her.”

“Yeah, we’ve already established that. You took her. What did you do, pluck her and eat her? You like roast duck, Liver Lips?”

His shoulders twitched. He did that rapid blinking thing and twisted his neck to loosen it up. A bead of sweat worked its way through thin tendrils of blond hair and trickled down his forehead. It looked muddy by the time it reached the corner of his eye. “Hell, I didn’t eat her. I give her to somebody.”

“Who?”

His pale gray eyes clouded over. “Just somebody wanted to play a trick on Mud Hen.”

“Who was this somebody?”

“If I give up his name, he’ll get me in trouble. And he can do it too.”

“So can I. A world of trouble. You’ve already given me enough to report to the insurance company. You’re the chicken thief, Liver Lips. And they’ll come after you hard. You have any idea how far they’d go to keep from paying out all that money?”

“How much money?” His attitude changed. If Liver Lips had a crafty side, this was it.

“More than you can ever repay in your lifetime.” I built on the fiction I was spinning. “They’ll see you prosecuted for grand theft. What does your record look like? Probably penny ante, right? Well, you made the big time with this.”

“For stealing a duck?”

I stared at the raunchy-looking man. Was this an act? “Answer my question. Who hired you to steal the duck?”

“Hired?”

Jeez. The guy hadn’t even been paid. He’d done it as a favor, or else someone had leverage on Richard Martinson.

“Who told you to take the duck? Who’d you give it to?”

“Her.”

“Her?”

“It’s a her. The duck, I mean. Quacky—”

“Yeah, I know. Who’d you give her to?”

Liver Lips crossed his arms over his chest and hugged himself tightly. “Oh shit! I hurt, man. They supposed to be getting me something for the pain. And the infection too. I gotta go check on it.”

“Okay, we’ll go together. Maybe I can help.”

“I can do it.” The words came out as a whine. “I ain’t no kid that needs babysitting.”

Despite his objections, I trod on his heels as he walked toward a counter. They’d made some big-time changes at the UNM Emergency Center. It was now housed in a new building called the Pavilion. But I was pretty sure this wasn’t the outpatient pharmacy. Liver Lips appeared ready to make a move. He did, but it wasn’t the one I expected; probably not the one he anticipated either.

He turned a corner and bumped squarely into a burly Albuquerque cop. Backpedaling, he held out his hands in a plea. “Sir, this here guy won’t leave me alone. Can you make him stop pestering me?”

The six-foot-two officer transferred his irritated look from Liver Lips to me. The shoulder microphone for his radio unit belched static, but he ignored it. “What’s going on?”

I took a quick peek at his name tag. “Corporal Hines, my name is Vinson, and I’m a licensed PI. I’m going to reach for my ID, okay?”

I whirled as the outside door crashed open. A man and a woman rushed inside with a little girl nursing a bloody hand wrapped in stained towels. Hines brushed by me to see if his help was needed. This momentary diversion was all Liver Lips needed. He’d vanished. I made a quick sweep of the hallways, but he had disappeared. Maybe Liver did have a crafty side after all.

Muttering under my breath, I headed for the parking structure to get my Impala. On the way I hit the speed dial on my cell. Del wasn’t pleased with the interview results, and I couldn’t blame him.

“So to sum it up,” he said, “you’re convinced Martinson kidnapped—excuse me, stole—the duck. You think he did it at the behest of someone else and has turned the bird over to that party. Other than that, the only thing you learned is that Millicent Muldren, the esteemed daughter of an old-line New Mexico ranching family, is called Mud Hen behind her back.”

“That about covers it. What do you want me to do now?”

“Nothing. I’ll let the client know Liver Lips is running. Probably back to the Deming area. He doesn’t seem to have personal ties anywhere else. Go back to your golf game, Vince.”

“Too late for that. And thanks, by the way. Today was the first time Paul and I have had any time together in a month.”

“The two of you still making it okay?”

“Smooth as silk. Except for our schedules. We seldom manage to meet up except at night.”

“That’s probably why it’s still working.” He hung up.

I was out of sorts, probably for the rest of the day. Paul’s schedule had reclaimed him, so I left the UNM parking structure and headed west on Lomas. The office was closed, but I’d been in the field working on a case since yesterday afternoon, so Hazel Harris, my office manager, had likely left a pile of documents for me to review and sign. Might as well get that chore over and done with instead of waiting for Monday.

Hazel and Charlie Weeks, the retired cop fast becoming a full-time investigator for me, had wrapped up a couple of cases. Charlie was not only a godsend to my business; he also kept my mothering, smothering office manager off my back. The two were becoming quite a pair around the office, although they continued to believe they hid the relationship well.

I settled down at my desk and reviewed the reports they’d left for me. After signing off on the documents, I went through the mail Hazel had left that required my attention, made a few notations, and dictated an answer or two before snapping off my desk lamp.

Still vaguely disgruntled, I swiveled my chair to the windows behind my desk and allowed the vista beyond the glass to slowly calm my nerves as I came to grips with my ill-defined sense of unease. It was not Del interrupting my pleasant afternoon with Paul—although that was a factor—as much as a sense of failure. Of leaving a job unfinished, a goal unattained. Liver Lips had outfoxed me, and that did not sit well.

A pleasant evening with Paul finally laid the thing to rest. Until the telephone rang at one fifteen in the morning.

2023-03-11 17:46:57 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-03-11 17:46:57 INFO - Step 14 - I restart app 2023-03-11 17:47:22 INFO - Step 15 - I open Books 2023-03-11 17:47:22 INFO - Button 'tabBooks' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:47:22 INFO - Step 16 - Open EBOOK book with READ action button and 'bookInfo' bookInfo on books screen 2023-03-11 17:47:23 INFO - Label 'lblBookName' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:47:24 INFO - Step 17 - Click READ action button on book details screen 2023-03-11 17:47:25 INFO - Button 'Read' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:47:25 INFO - Step 18 - The BLACK_TEXT_ON_WHITE background is correct 2023-03-11 17:47:25 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-03-11 17:47:26 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-03-11 17:47:26 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-03-11 17:47:28 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-03-11 17:47:29 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-03-11 17:47:29 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-03-11 17:47:29 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-03-11 17:47:30 INFO -

Chapter 1

Ten days later, Albuquerque, New Mexico

I JERKED the cell phone away from my ear and looked at it as if it had lost its mind—or its chip. Del Dahlman, a local attorney, wanted me to drop everything and run down to the UNM Emergency Center to interview a man named Richard Martinson. When he told me why, I assumed he was kidding. He had to be.

“You want me to go question a ducknapper? There’s no such thing. He’s just a plain, ordinary chicken thief.”

“Whatever,” Del said. “I need you to catch him before he leaves the emergency room.”

This was simply too good to let go. “Have you called in the FBI yet?”

“Don’t be an ass,” Del snapped.

“Donkeys now? What is this, a menagerie run amok? Who did it? The pigs? Good Lord, it’s Orwell’s Animal Farm come to life.”

“Dammit, Vince, I’m serious. This is serious. I need you to get over there right away.”

I stared at the bright blue sky on this cloudless Saturday afternoon and considered hanging up on Del. I stood on the fourth tee of the golf course at the North Valley Country Club with Paul Barton. Although we lived together, it was a rare occasion when Paul and I could share the daylight hours. Between my confidential investigations business and Paul’s schedule—UNM grad school summer courses and an aquatic director’s job at the country club—we were the proverbial ships passing in the night.

I resented Del’s intrusion, but he and I went back a long way—some of it sweet, some of it bittersweet, and some downright sour.

“You need to get a move on,” he said. “You’ve got to get to him before they let him go. His name’s Richard Martinson, but… but they call him Liver Lips.” Del didn’t like playing the straight man.

“Liver Lips? Calves’ liver or…. No, don’t tell me. Let me guess. Goose liver.”

“You’re wasting my time, BJ.” He always called me Vince, a carryover from the days when we were a couple. Anytime he resorted to addressing me as BJ like the rest of the world, he was pissed.

“Hey, you called me. Right in the middle of my backswing, as a matter of fact.”

“Are you going to do it or not?”

I sighed. One of my better clients, Del commanded my attention. “Okay. Give me the details. There’s really a lawsuit on this thing?”

“No, it’s not actually a suit… yet.”

“Then why is your firm involved? More to the point, why are you involving me?”

He went defensive. “We’re New Mexico counsel for the Greater Southwest Ranchers Insurance Company or GSR, as they liked to be called, and the VP handling their problem and I are old friends. At this point I’m doing this as a favor to him. At any rate, the missing bird’s name is Quacky Quack the Second. This—”

“Quacky what?”

“Shut up, Vince.”

I snickered through the rest of his briefing, hung up, and turned to my golfing companion. Paul got as good a laugh out of it as I had. In fact, we both broke up a couple of times during the retelling.

I DO not like walking into a situation I don’t understand, and I damned well didn’t understand this one. But I had no trouble locating Martinson in the waiting room at the hospital. Liver Lips. The young man’s nickname described him perfectly. His thick, purple-hued oral projections drew my eye like a magnet. Only later did I notice he was skinny, seedy, and carried a generally disreputable air. Gray eyes darted here and there as if he were constantly searching for a bolt-hole. The man’s scalp glistened through thin strands of frizzy blond hair. Whether he was talking or listening or simply idle, his dark tongue periodically snaked out to wash those heavy lips. Seldom had I been so thoroughly repulsed by another’s physical appearance.

He looked at me blankly after I handed over my card and introduced myself. “A private eye, huh. What you want with me?”

“I need to ask you a few questions.” I nodded at the bandages covering his forearms. “What happened?”

“Had a fight with a thorn bush. Frigging bush won.” He went for humor, glancing up through thin, colorless lashes to see if it had worked.

I pointed to the red veins snaking up out of the white bandage on his right arm just short of his elbows. “Thorn bushes didn’t give you that infection. That’s blood poisoning. How’d you get it?”

“Tangled with the wrong bush, I guess. Then didn’t get it treated. Turned bad on me, I guess.”

“Come on, I’ll give you a ride down to my office where we can talk in private.”

“Ain’t got time. Gotta get outta here. I been here six frigging hours.”

“Okay, I’ll call Lt. Eugene Enriquez down at the police department, and we’ll have this talk at APD.”

He blinked rapidly three times. “No cops, man. Don’t need no cops. I ain’t done nothing, so leave me alone.”

“What are you doing up here? You live down in Deming, don’t you?” I drew on the thin biography Del had provided.

“Ain’t no law against a man visiting the city. I guess that’s what they do all that advertising on TV for. You know, to get me to come up here and spend my money.”

“You want to tell me about it?”

“About what?” He seemed genuinely perplexed by my question.

“About stealing a valuable… bird.” If I’d said “duck” I’d have burst out laughing.

“Don’t guess I know what you’re talking about.”

“You do a lot of guessing, Richard. But I don’t think the sheriff of Luna County would have sicced me on you if he was just guessing.”

“Hidalgo,” he blurted.

“What?”

“Sheriff of Hidalgo County.”

“Okay, now that you’ve admitted you know all about the theft, tell me about it.”

“Didn’t admit nothing.”

“You know where the abduction… uh, theft took place. Stop wasting my time. What did you want with a prize duck named….” I stopped, unable to call a bird by that ridiculous name.

“Quacky Quack the Second,” he said. “That’s what old Mud Hen calls her. Ain’t that a hoot?”

“Mud Hen?”

“Millicent Muldren. Everybody calls her Mud Hen.”

“She’s the duck’s owner?”

“Yeah. She’s run the Lazy M Ranch since her old man died.”

“Why’d you steal her duck?”

“Who says I did?”

I improvised. “About everybody in the countryside. Police chief, sheriff, Mrs. Muldren. There’s a warrant out for your arrest. Talk to me, and maybe I can do something about that.”

Old Liver Lips wasn’t as dumb as he looked. Those blood-suffused appendages quivered a couple of times before he squared his thin shoulders. “Ain’t nobody gonna arrest me for nothing, I guess. Who’d press charges on something like that?”

“Well, Mud Hen for one, and the insurance company for another.”

“Insurance company?”

“You didn’t know the owner had insured her property?”

“Shoot, I guess there ain’t no insurance company in the world that’d insure a frigging duck.”

I didn’t know much more than he did, but I couldn’t let up on him now. “Then you’d guess wrong. They’ll insure soap bubbles if you pay the premiums.”

Liver Lips wiggled in his chair, looking distinctly uncomfortable. “Uh… you said something about a warrant?”

Flying totally blind, I had no idea if a warrant existed for this character. In fact, I didn’t even know why he was suspected of the theft. Or how Del found out he’d be at the UNM Emergency Center today.

“Yes, but I can deal with that if you give me what I want.”

“Like what?”

“Like what have you done with Qua… with the duck?” His eyes slid away as he opened his mouth and licked his lips. I held up a hand. “Don’t bother to deny it. You’re caught flat out. Man up and admit it. Where’s the duck?”

“Dunno.” The word came out in a whisper.

“Why not?”

“Somebody took her.”

“Yeah, we’ve already established that. You took her. What did you do, pluck her and eat her? You like roast duck, Liver Lips?”

His shoulders twitched. He did that rapid blinking thing and twisted his neck to loosen it up. A bead of sweat worked its way through thin tendrils of blond hair and trickled down his forehead. It looked muddy by the time it reached the corner of his eye. “Hell, I didn’t eat her. I give her to somebody.”

“Who?”

His pale gray eyes clouded over. “Just somebody wanted to play a trick on Mud Hen.”

“Who was this somebody?”

“If I give up his name, he’ll get me in trouble. And he can do it too.”

“So can I. A world of trouble. You’ve already given me enough to report to the insurance company. You’re the chicken thief, Liver Lips. And they’ll come after you hard. You have any idea how far they’d go to keep from paying out all that money?”

“How much money?” His attitude changed. If Liver Lips had a crafty side, this was it.

“More than you can ever repay in your lifetime.” I built on the fiction I was spinning. “They’ll see you prosecuted for grand theft. What does your record look like? Probably penny ante, right? Well, you made the big time with this.”

“For stealing a duck?”

I stared at the raunchy-looking man. Was this an act? “Answer my question. Who hired you to steal the duck?”

“Hired?”

Jeez. The guy hadn’t even been paid. He’d done it as a favor, or else someone had leverage on Richard Martinson.

“Who told you to take the duck? Who’d you give it to?”

“Her.”

“Her?”

“It’s a her. The duck, I mean. Quacky—”

“Yeah, I know. Who’d you give her to?”

Liver Lips crossed his arms over his chest and hugged himself tightly. “Oh shit! I hurt, man. They supposed to be getting me something for the pain. And the infection too. I gotta go check on it.”

“Okay, we’ll go together. Maybe I can help.”

“I can do it.” The words came out as a whine. “I ain’t no kid that needs babysitting.”

Despite his objections, I trod on his heels as he walked toward a counter. They’d made some big-time changes at the UNM Emergency Center. It was now housed in a new building called the Pavilion. But I was pretty sure this wasn’t the outpatient pharmacy. Liver Lips appeared ready to make a move. He did, but it wasn’t the one I expected; probably not the one he anticipated either.

He turned a corner and bumped squarely into a burly Albuquerque cop. Backpedaling, he held out his hands in a plea. “Sir, this here guy won’t leave me alone. Can you make him stop pestering me?”

The six-foot-two officer transferred his irritated look from Liver Lips to me. The shoulder microphone for his radio unit belched static, but he ignored it. “What’s going on?”

I took a quick peek at his name tag. “Corporal Hines, my name is Vinson, and I’m a licensed PI. I’m going to reach for my ID, okay?”

I whirled as the outside door crashed open. A man and a woman rushed inside with a little girl nursing a bloody hand wrapped in stained towels. Hines brushed by me to see if his help was needed. This momentary diversion was all Liver Lips needed. He’d vanished. I made a quick sweep of the hallways, but he had disappeared. Maybe Liver did have a crafty side after all.

Muttering under my breath, I headed for the parking structure to get my Impala. On the way I hit the speed dial on my cell. Del wasn’t pleased with the interview results, and I couldn’t blame him.

“So to sum it up,” he said, “you’re convinced Martinson kidnapped—excuse me, stole—the duck. You think he did it at the behest of someone else and has turned the bird over to that party. Other than that, the only thing you learned is that Millicent Muldren, the esteemed daughter of an old-line New Mexico ranching family, is called Mud Hen behind her back.”

“That about covers it. What do you want me to do now?”

“Nothing. I’ll let the client know Liver Lips is running. Probably back to the Deming area. He doesn’t seem to have personal ties anywhere else. Go back to your golf game, Vince.”

“Too late for that. And thanks, by the way. Today was the first time Paul and I have had any time together in a month.”

“The two of you still making it okay?”

“Smooth as silk. Except for our schedules. We seldom manage to meet up except at night.”

“That’s probably why it’s still working.” He hung up.

I was out of sorts, probably for the rest of the day. Paul’s schedule had reclaimed him, so I left the UNM parking structure and headed west on Lomas. The office was closed, but I’d been in the field working on a case since yesterday afternoon, so Hazel Harris, my office manager, had likely left a pile of documents for me to review and sign. Might as well get that chore over and done with instead of waiting for Monday.

Hazel and Charlie Weeks, the retired cop fast becoming a full-time investigator for me, had wrapped up a couple of cases. Charlie was not only a godsend to my business; he also kept my mothering, smothering office manager off my back. The two were becoming quite a pair around the office, although they continued to believe they hid the relationship well.

I settled down at my desk and reviewed the reports they’d left for me. After signing off on the documents, I went through the mail Hazel had left that required my attention, made a few notations, and dictated an answer or two before snapping off my desk lamp.

Still vaguely disgruntled, I swiveled my chair to the windows behind my desk and allowed the vista beyond the glass to slowly calm my nerves as I came to grips with my ill-defined sense of unease. It was not Del interrupting my pleasant afternoon with Paul—although that was a factor—as much as a sense of failure. Of leaving a job unfinished, a goal unattained. Liver Lips had outfoxed me, and that did not sit well.

A pleasant evening with Paul finally laid the thing to rest. Until the telephone rang at one fifteen in the morning.

2023-03-11 17:47:30 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-03-11 17:47:30 INFO - Step 19 - I return to previous screen from epub 2023-03-11 17:47:31 INFO - Button 'btnBack' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:47:31 INFO - Step 20 - Click READ action button on book details screen 2023-03-11 17:47:32 INFO - Button 'Read' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:47:32 INFO - Step 21 - The BLACK_TEXT_ON_WHITE background is correct 2023-03-11 17:47:33 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-03-11 17:47:33 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-03-11 17:47:35 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-03-11 17:47:35 INFO -

Chapter 1

Ten days later, Albuquerque, New Mexico

I JERKED the cell phone away from my ear and looked at it as if it had lost its mind—or its chip. Del Dahlman, a local attorney, wanted me to drop everything and run down to the UNM Emergency Center to interview a man named Richard Martinson. When he told me why, I assumed he was kidding. He had to be.

“You want me to go question a ducknapper? There’s no such thing. He’s just a plain, ordinary chicken thief.”

“Whatever,” Del said. “I need you to catch him before he leaves the emergency room.”

This was simply too good to let go. “Have you called in the FBI yet?”

“Don’t be an ass,” Del snapped.

“Donkeys now? What is this, a menagerie run amok? Who did it? The pigs? Good Lord, it’s Orwell’s Animal Farm come to life.”

“Dammit, Vince, I’m serious. This is serious. I need you to get over there right away.”

I stared at the bright blue sky on this cloudless Saturday afternoon and considered hanging up on Del. I stood on the fourth tee of the golf course at the North Valley Country Club with Paul Barton. Although we lived together, it was a rare occasion when Paul and I could share the daylight hours. Between my confidential investigations business and Paul’s schedule—UNM grad school summer courses and an aquatic director’s job at the country club—we were the proverbial ships passing in the night.

I resented Del’s intrusion, but he and I went back a long way—some of it sweet, some of it bittersweet, and some downright sour.

“You need to get a move on,” he said. “You’ve got to get to him before they let him go. His name’s Richard Martinson, but… but they call him Liver Lips.” Del didn’t like playing the straight man.

“Liver Lips? Calves’ liver or…. No, don’t tell me. Let me guess. Goose liver.”

“You’re wasting my time, BJ.” He always called me Vince, a carryover from the days when we were a couple. Anytime he resorted to addressing me as BJ like the rest of the world, he was pissed.

“Hey, you called me. Right in the middle of my backswing, as a matter of fact.”

“Are you going to do it or not?”

I sighed. One of my better clients, Del commanded my attention. “Okay. Give me the details. There’s really a lawsuit on this thing?”

“No, it’s not actually a suit… yet.”

“Then why is your firm involved? More to the point, why are you involving me?”

He went defensive. “We’re New Mexico counsel for the Greater Southwest Ranchers Insurance Company or GSR, as they liked to be called, and the VP handling their problem and I are old friends. At this point I’m doing this as a favor to him. At any rate, the missing bird’s name is Quacky Quack the Second. This—”

“Quacky what?”

“Shut up, Vince.”

I snickered through the rest of his briefing, hung up, and turned to my golfing companion. Paul got as good a laugh out of it as I had. In fact, we both broke up a couple of times during the retelling.

I DO not like walking into a situation I don’t understand, and I damned well didn’t understand this one. But I had no trouble locating Martinson in the waiting room at the hospital. Liver Lips. The young man’s nickname described him perfectly. His thick, purple-hued oral projections drew my eye like a magnet. Only later did I notice he was skinny, seedy, and carried a generally disreputable air. Gray eyes darted here and there as if he were constantly searching for a bolt-hole. The man’s scalp glistened through thin strands of frizzy blond hair. Whether he was talking or listening or simply idle, his dark tongue periodically snaked out to wash those heavy lips. Seldom had I been so thoroughly repulsed by another’s physical appearance.

He looked at me blankly after I handed over my card and introduced myself. “A private eye, huh. What you want with me?”

“I need to ask you a few questions.” I nodded at the bandages covering his forearms. “What happened?”

“Had a fight with a thorn bush. Frigging bush won.” He went for humor, glancing up through thin, colorless lashes to see if it had worked.

I pointed to the red veins snaking up out of the white bandage on his right arm just short of his elbows. “Thorn bushes didn’t give you that infection. That’s blood poisoning. How’d you get it?”

“Tangled with the wrong bush, I guess. Then didn’t get it treated. Turned bad on me, I guess.”

“Come on, I’ll give you a ride down to my office where we can talk in private.”

“Ain’t got time. Gotta get outta here. I been here six frigging hours.”

“Okay, I’ll call Lt. Eugene Enriquez down at the police department, and we’ll have this talk at APD.”

He blinked rapidly three times. “No cops, man. Don’t need no cops. I ain’t done nothing, so leave me alone.”

“What are you doing up here? You live down in Deming, don’t you?” I drew on the thin biography Del had provided.

“Ain’t no law against a man visiting the city. I guess that’s what they do all that advertising on TV for. You know, to get me to come up here and spend my money.”

“You want to tell me about it?”

“About what?” He seemed genuinely perplexed by my question.

“About stealing a valuable… bird.” If I’d said “duck” I’d have burst out laughing.

“Don’t guess I know what you’re talking about.”

“You do a lot of guessing, Richard. But I don’t think the sheriff of Luna County would have sicced me on you if he was just guessing.”

“Hidalgo,” he blurted.

“What?”

“Sheriff of Hidalgo County.”

“Okay, now that you’ve admitted you know all about the theft, tell me about it.”

“Didn’t admit nothing.”

“You know where the abduction… uh, theft took place. Stop wasting my time. What did you want with a prize duck named….” I stopped, unable to call a bird by that ridiculous name.

“Quacky Quack the Second,” he said. “That’s what old Mud Hen calls her. Ain’t that a hoot?”

“Mud Hen?”

“Millicent Muldren. Everybody calls her Mud Hen.”

“She’s the duck’s owner?”

“Yeah. She’s run the Lazy M Ranch since her old man died.”

“Why’d you steal her duck?”

“Who says I did?”

I improvised. “About everybody in the countryside. Police chief, sheriff, Mrs. Muldren. There’s a warrant out for your arrest. Talk to me, and maybe I can do something about that.”

Old Liver Lips wasn’t as dumb as he looked. Those blood-suffused appendages quivered a couple of times before he squared his thin shoulders. “Ain’t nobody gonna arrest me for nothing, I guess. Who’d press charges on something like that?”

“Well, Mud Hen for one, and the insurance company for another.”

“Insurance company?”

“You didn’t know the owner had insured her property?”

“Shoot, I guess there ain’t no insurance company in the world that’d insure a frigging duck.”

I didn’t know much more than he did, but I couldn’t let up on him now. “Then you’d guess wrong. They’ll insure soap bubbles if you pay the premiums.”

Liver Lips wiggled in his chair, looking distinctly uncomfortable. “Uh… you said something about a warrant?”

Flying totally blind, I had no idea if a warrant existed for this character. In fact, I didn’t even know why he was suspected of the theft. Or how Del found out he’d be at the UNM Emergency Center today.

“Yes, but I can deal with that if you give me what I want.”

“Like what?”

“Like what have you done with Qua… with the duck?” His eyes slid away as he opened his mouth and licked his lips. I held up a hand. “Don’t bother to deny it. You’re caught flat out. Man up and admit it. Where’s the duck?”

“Dunno.” The word came out in a whisper.

“Why not?”

“Somebody took her.”

“Yeah, we’ve already established that. You took her. What did you do, pluck her and eat her? You like roast duck, Liver Lips?”

His shoulders twitched. He did that rapid blinking thing and twisted his neck to loosen it up. A bead of sweat worked its way through thin tendrils of blond hair and trickled down his forehead. It looked muddy by the time it reached the corner of his eye. “Hell, I didn’t eat her. I give her to somebody.”

“Who?”

His pale gray eyes clouded over. “Just somebody wanted to play a trick on Mud Hen.”

“Who was this somebody?”

“If I give up his name, he’ll get me in trouble. And he can do it too.”

“So can I. A world of trouble. You’ve already given me enough to report to the insurance company. You’re the chicken thief, Liver Lips. And they’ll come after you hard. You have any idea how far they’d go to keep from paying out all that money?”

“How much money?” His attitude changed. If Liver Lips had a crafty side, this was it.

“More than you can ever repay in your lifetime.” I built on the fiction I was spinning. “They’ll see you prosecuted for grand theft. What does your record look like? Probably penny ante, right? Well, you made the big time with this.”

“For stealing a duck?”

I stared at the raunchy-looking man. Was this an act? “Answer my question. Who hired you to steal the duck?”

“Hired?”

Jeez. The guy hadn’t even been paid. He’d done it as a favor, or else someone had leverage on Richard Martinson.

“Who told you to take the duck? Who’d you give it to?”

“Her.”

“Her?”

“It’s a her. The duck, I mean. Quacky—”

“Yeah, I know. Who’d you give her to?”

Liver Lips crossed his arms over his chest and hugged himself tightly. “Oh shit! I hurt, man. They supposed to be getting me something for the pain. And the infection too. I gotta go check on it.”

“Okay, we’ll go together. Maybe I can help.”

“I can do it.” The words came out as a whine. “I ain’t no kid that needs babysitting.”

Despite his objections, I trod on his heels as he walked toward a counter. They’d made some big-time changes at the UNM Emergency Center. It was now housed in a new building called the Pavilion. But I was pretty sure this wasn’t the outpatient pharmacy. Liver Lips appeared ready to make a move. He did, but it wasn’t the one I expected; probably not the one he anticipated either.

He turned a corner and bumped squarely into a burly Albuquerque cop. Backpedaling, he held out his hands in a plea. “Sir, this here guy won’t leave me alone. Can you make him stop pestering me?”

The six-foot-two officer transferred his irritated look from Liver Lips to me. The shoulder microphone for his radio unit belched static, but he ignored it. “What’s going on?”

I took a quick peek at his name tag. “Corporal Hines, my name is Vinson, and I’m a licensed PI. I’m going to reach for my ID, okay?”

I whirled as the outside door crashed open. A man and a woman rushed inside with a little girl nursing a bloody hand wrapped in stained towels. Hines brushed by me to see if his help was needed. This momentary diversion was all Liver Lips needed. He’d vanished. I made a quick sweep of the hallways, but he had disappeared. Maybe Liver did have a crafty side after all.

Muttering under my breath, I headed for the parking structure to get my Impala. On the way I hit the speed dial on my cell. Del wasn’t pleased with the interview results, and I couldn’t blame him.

“So to sum it up,” he said, “you’re convinced Martinson kidnapped—excuse me, stole—the duck. You think he did it at the behest of someone else and has turned the bird over to that party. Other than that, the only thing you learned is that Millicent Muldren, the esteemed daughter of an old-line New Mexico ranching family, is called Mud Hen behind her back.”

“That about covers it. What do you want me to do now?”

“Nothing. I’ll let the client know Liver Lips is running. Probably back to the Deming area. He doesn’t seem to have personal ties anywhere else. Go back to your golf game, Vince.”

“Too late for that. And thanks, by the way. Today was the first time Paul and I have had any time together in a month.”

“The two of you still making it okay?”

“Smooth as silk. Except for our schedules. We seldom manage to meet up except at night.”

“That’s probably why it’s still working.” He hung up.

I was out of sorts, probably for the rest of the day. Paul’s schedule had reclaimed him, so I left the UNM parking structure and headed west on Lomas. The office was closed, but I’d been in the field working on a case since yesterday afternoon, so Hazel Harris, my office manager, had likely left a pile of documents for me to review and sign. Might as well get that chore over and done with instead of waiting for Monday.

Hazel and Charlie Weeks, the retired cop fast becoming a full-time investigator for me, had wrapped up a couple of cases. Charlie was not only a godsend to my business; he also kept my mothering, smothering office manager off my back. The two were becoming quite a pair around the office, although they continued to believe they hid the relationship well.

I settled down at my desk and reviewed the reports they’d left for me. After signing off on the documents, I went through the mail Hazel had left that required my attention, made a few notations, and dictated an answer or two before snapping off my desk lamp.

Still vaguely disgruntled, I swiveled my chair to the windows behind my desk and allowed the vista beyond the glass to slowly calm my nerves as I came to grips with my ill-defined sense of unease. It was not Del interrupting my pleasant afternoon with Paul—although that was a factor—as much as a sense of failure. Of leaving a job unfinished, a goal unattained. Liver Lips had outfoxed me, and that did not sit well.

A pleasant evening with Paul finally laid the thing to rest. Until the telephone rang at one fifteen in the morning.

2023-03-11 17:47:35 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-03-11 17:47:35 INFO - Step 22 - I open font settings 2023-03-11 17:47:35 INFO - Button 'btnFontSettings' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:47:36 INFO - Step 23 - I change contrast to BLACK_TEXT_ON_SEPIA 2023-03-11 17:47:36 INFO - Button 'setThemeSepia' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:47:37 INFO - Step 24 - The BLACK_TEXT_ON_SEPIA background is correct 2023-03-11 17:47:37 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-03-11 17:47:37 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-03-11 17:47:38 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-03-11 17:47:38 INFO -

Chapter 1

Ten days later, Albuquerque, New Mexico

I JERKED the cell phone away from my ear and looked at it as if it had lost its mind—or its chip. Del Dahlman, a local attorney, wanted me to drop everything and run down to the UNM Emergency Center to interview a man named Richard Martinson. When he told me why, I assumed he was kidding. He had to be.

“You want me to go question a ducknapper? There’s no such thing. He’s just a plain, ordinary chicken thief.”

“Whatever,” Del said. “I need you to catch him before he leaves the emergency room.”

This was simply too good to let go. “Have you called in the FBI yet?”

“Don’t be an ass,” Del snapped.

“Donkeys now? What is this, a menagerie run amok? Who did it? The pigs? Good Lord, it’s Orwell’s Animal Farm come to life.”

“Dammit, Vince, I’m serious. This is serious. I need you to get over there right away.”

I stared at the bright blue sky on this cloudless Saturday afternoon and considered hanging up on Del. I stood on the fourth tee of the golf course at the North Valley Country Club with Paul Barton. Although we lived together, it was a rare occasion when Paul and I could share the daylight hours. Between my confidential investigations business and Paul’s schedule—UNM grad school summer courses and an aquatic director’s job at the country club—we were the proverbial ships passing in the night.

I resented Del’s intrusion, but he and I went back a long way—some of it sweet, some of it bittersweet, and some downright sour.

“You need to get a move on,” he said. “You’ve got to get to him before they let him go. His name’s Richard Martinson, but… but they call him Liver Lips.” Del didn’t like playing the straight man.

“Liver Lips? Calves’ liver or…. No, don’t tell me. Let me guess. Goose liver.”

“You’re wasting my time, BJ.” He always called me Vince, a carryover from the days when we were a couple. Anytime he resorted to addressing me as BJ like the rest of the world, he was pissed.

“Hey, you called me. Right in the middle of my backswing, as a matter of fact.”

“Are you going to do it or not?”

I sighed. One of my better clients, Del commanded my attention. “Okay. Give me the details. There’s really a lawsuit on this thing?”

“No, it’s not actually a suit… yet.”

“Then why is your firm involved? More to the point, why are you involving me?”

He went defensive. “We’re New Mexico counsel for the Greater Southwest Ranchers Insurance Company or GSR, as they liked to be called, and the VP handling their problem and I are old friends. At this point I’m doing this as a favor to him. At any rate, the missing bird’s name is Quacky Quack the Second. This—”

“Quacky what?”

“Shut up, Vince.”

I snickered through the rest of his briefing, hung up, and turned to my golfing companion. Paul got as good a laugh out of it as I had. In fact, we both broke up a couple of times during the retelling.

I DO not like walking into a situation I don’t understand, and I damned well didn’t understand this one. But I had no trouble locating Martinson in the waiting room at the hospital. Liver Lips. The young man’s nickname described him perfectly. His thick, purple-hued oral projections drew my eye like a magnet. Only later did I notice he was skinny, seedy, and carried a generally disreputable air. Gray eyes darted here and there as if he were constantly searching for a bolt-hole. The man’s scalp glistened through thin strands of frizzy blond hair. Whether he was talking or listening or simply idle, his dark tongue periodically snaked out to wash those heavy lips. Seldom had I been so thoroughly repulsed by another’s physical appearance.

He looked at me blankly after I handed over my card and introduced myself. “A private eye, huh. What you want with me?”

“I need to ask you a few questions.” I nodded at the bandages covering his forearms. “What happened?”

“Had a fight with a thorn bush. Frigging bush won.” He went for humor, glancing up through thin, colorless lashes to see if it had worked.

I pointed to the red veins snaking up out of the white bandage on his right arm just short of his elbows. “Thorn bushes didn’t give you that infection. That’s blood poisoning. How’d you get it?”

“Tangled with the wrong bush, I guess. Then didn’t get it treated. Turned bad on me, I guess.”

“Come on, I’ll give you a ride down to my office where we can talk in private.”

“Ain’t got time. Gotta get outta here. I been here six frigging hours.”

“Okay, I’ll call Lt. Eugene Enriquez down at the police department, and we’ll have this talk at APD.”

He blinked rapidly three times. “No cops, man. Don’t need no cops. I ain’t done nothing, so leave me alone.”

“What are you doing up here? You live down in Deming, don’t you?” I drew on the thin biography Del had provided.

“Ain’t no law against a man visiting the city. I guess that’s what they do all that advertising on TV for. You know, to get me to come up here and spend my money.”

“You want to tell me about it?”

“About what?” He seemed genuinely perplexed by my question.

“About stealing a valuable… bird.” If I’d said “duck” I’d have burst out laughing.

“Don’t guess I know what you’re talking about.”

“You do a lot of guessing, Richard. But I don’t think the sheriff of Luna County would have sicced me on you if he was just guessing.”

“Hidalgo,” he blurted.

“What?”

“Sheriff of Hidalgo County.”

“Okay, now that you’ve admitted you know all about the theft, tell me about it.”

“Didn’t admit nothing.”

“You know where the abduction… uh, theft took place. Stop wasting my time. What did you want with a prize duck named….” I stopped, unable to call a bird by that ridiculous name.

“Quacky Quack the Second,” he said. “That’s what old Mud Hen calls her. Ain’t that a hoot?”

“Mud Hen?”

“Millicent Muldren. Everybody calls her Mud Hen.”

“She’s the duck’s owner?”

“Yeah. She’s run the Lazy M Ranch since her old man died.”

“Why’d you steal her duck?”

“Who says I did?”

I improvised. “About everybody in the countryside. Police chief, sheriff, Mrs. Muldren. There’s a warrant out for your arrest. Talk to me, and maybe I can do something about that.”

Old Liver Lips wasn’t as dumb as he looked. Those blood-suffused appendages quivered a couple of times before he squared his thin shoulders. “Ain’t nobody gonna arrest me for nothing, I guess. Who’d press charges on something like that?”

“Well, Mud Hen for one, and the insurance company for another.”

“Insurance company?”

“You didn’t know the owner had insured her property?”

“Shoot, I guess there ain’t no insurance company in the world that’d insure a frigging duck.”

I didn’t know much more than he did, but I couldn’t let up on him now. “Then you’d guess wrong. They’ll insure soap bubbles if you pay the premiums.”

Liver Lips wiggled in his chair, looking distinctly uncomfortable. “Uh… you said something about a warrant?”

Flying totally blind, I had no idea if a warrant existed for this character. In fact, I didn’t even know why he was suspected of the theft. Or how Del found out he’d be at the UNM Emergency Center today.

“Yes, but I can deal with that if you give me what I want.”

“Like what?”

“Like what have you done with Qua… with the duck?” His eyes slid away as he opened his mouth and licked his lips. I held up a hand. “Don’t bother to deny it. You’re caught flat out. Man up and admit it. Where’s the duck?”

“Dunno.” The word came out in a whisper.

“Why not?”

“Somebody took her.”

“Yeah, we’ve already established that. You took her. What did you do, pluck her and eat her? You like roast duck, Liver Lips?”

His shoulders twitched. He did that rapid blinking thing and twisted his neck to loosen it up. A bead of sweat worked its way through thin tendrils of blond hair and trickled down his forehead. It looked muddy by the time it reached the corner of his eye. “Hell, I didn’t eat her. I give her to somebody.”

“Who?”

His pale gray eyes clouded over. “Just somebody wanted to play a trick on Mud Hen.”

“Who was this somebody?”

“If I give up his name, he’ll get me in trouble. And he can do it too.”

“So can I. A world of trouble. You’ve already given me enough to report to the insurance company. You’re the chicken thief, Liver Lips. And they’ll come after you hard. You have any idea how far they’d go to keep from paying out all that money?”

“How much money?” His attitude changed. If Liver Lips had a crafty side, this was it.

“More than you can ever repay in your lifetime.” I built on the fiction I was spinning. “They’ll see you prosecuted for grand theft. What does your record look like? Probably penny ante, right? Well, you made the big time with this.”

“For stealing a duck?”

I stared at the raunchy-looking man. Was this an act? “Answer my question. Who hired you to steal the duck?”

“Hired?”

Jeez. The guy hadn’t even been paid. He’d done it as a favor, or else someone had leverage on Richard Martinson.

“Who told you to take the duck? Who’d you give it to?”

“Her.”

“Her?”

“It’s a her. The duck, I mean. Quacky—”

“Yeah, I know. Who’d you give her to?”

Liver Lips crossed his arms over his chest and hugged himself tightly. “Oh shit! I hurt, man. They supposed to be getting me something for the pain. And the infection too. I gotta go check on it.”

“Okay, we’ll go together. Maybe I can help.”

“I can do it.” The words came out as a whine. “I ain’t no kid that needs babysitting.”

Despite his objections, I trod on his heels as he walked toward a counter. They’d made some big-time changes at the UNM Emergency Center. It was now housed in a new building called the Pavilion. But I was pretty sure this wasn’t the outpatient pharmacy. Liver Lips appeared ready to make a move. He did, but it wasn’t the one I expected; probably not the one he anticipated either.

He turned a corner and bumped squarely into a burly Albuquerque cop. Backpedaling, he held out his hands in a plea. “Sir, this here guy won’t leave me alone. Can you make him stop pestering me?”

The six-foot-two officer transferred his irritated look from Liver Lips to me. The shoulder microphone for his radio unit belched static, but he ignored it. “What’s going on?”

I took a quick peek at his name tag. “Corporal Hines, my name is Vinson, and I’m a licensed PI. I’m going to reach for my ID, okay?”

I whirled as the outside door crashed open. A man and a woman rushed inside with a little girl nursing a bloody hand wrapped in stained towels. Hines brushed by me to see if his help was needed. This momentary diversion was all Liver Lips needed. He’d vanished. I made a quick sweep of the hallways, but he had disappeared. Maybe Liver did have a crafty side after all.

Muttering under my breath, I headed for the parking structure to get my Impala. On the way I hit the speed dial on my cell. Del wasn’t pleased with the interview results, and I couldn’t blame him.

“So to sum it up,” he said, “you’re convinced Martinson kidnapped—excuse me, stole—the duck. You think he did it at the behest of someone else and has turned the bird over to that party. Other than that, the only thing you learned is that Millicent Muldren, the esteemed daughter of an old-line New Mexico ranching family, is called Mud Hen behind her back.”

“That about covers it. What do you want me to do now?”

“Nothing. I’ll let the client know Liver Lips is running. Probably back to the Deming area. He doesn’t seem to have personal ties anywhere else. Go back to your golf game, Vince.”

“Too late for that. And thanks, by the way. Today was the first time Paul and I have had any time together in a month.”

“The two of you still making it okay?”

“Smooth as silk. Except for our schedules. We seldom manage to meet up except at night.”

“That’s probably why it’s still working.” He hung up.

I was out of sorts, probably for the rest of the day. Paul’s schedule had reclaimed him, so I left the UNM parking structure and headed west on Lomas. The office was closed, but I’d been in the field working on a case since yesterday afternoon, so Hazel Harris, my office manager, had likely left a pile of documents for me to review and sign. Might as well get that chore over and done with instead of waiting for Monday.

Hazel and Charlie Weeks, the retired cop fast becoming a full-time investigator for me, had wrapped up a couple of cases. Charlie was not only a godsend to my business; he also kept my mothering, smothering office manager off my back. The two were becoming quite a pair around the office, although they continued to believe they hid the relationship well.

I settled down at my desk and reviewed the reports they’d left for me. After signing off on the documents, I went through the mail Hazel had left that required my attention, made a few notations, and dictated an answer or two before snapping off my desk lamp.

Still vaguely disgruntled, I swiveled my chair to the windows behind my desk and allowed the vista beyond the glass to slowly calm my nerves as I came to grips with my ill-defined sense of unease. It was not Del interrupting my pleasant afternoon with Paul—although that was a factor—as much as a sense of failure. Of leaving a job unfinished, a goal unattained. Liver Lips had outfoxed me, and that did not sit well.

A pleasant evening with Paul finally laid the thing to rest. Until the telephone rang at one fifteen in the morning.

2023-03-11 17:47:38 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-03-11 17:47:38 INFO - Taking screenshot 2023-03-11 17:47:39 INFO - Test finished - logging out 2023-03-11 17:47:40 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:47:44 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:47:45 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:47:46 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:47:48 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Getting text from element 2023-03-11 17:47:48 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Getting text from element 2023-03-11 17:47:48 INFO - Button 'Log out' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:47:48 INFO - Button 'Log in' :: Getting text from element 2023-03-11 17:47:52 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Getting text from element 2023-03-11 17:47:53 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Getting text from element 2023-03-11 17:47:53 INFO - Unlocking credential for current thread 2023-03-11 17:47:53 INFO - isLoggerNullAfterAnnotation-framework.utilities.Logger@1dfe12c0

2023-03-11 17:31:01 INFO - Scenario 'Font settings: Check of font style' start 2023-03-11 17:31:01 INFO - Setting application driver using the server on 'https://hub-cloud.browserstack.com/wd/hub' 2023-03-11 17:31:49 INFO - Application on platform 'ANDROID' is ready... 2023-03-11 17:31:49 INFO - Session id - a9fc202ad60a8b81989f8fc4e4bae4fbca8b4851 2023-03-11 17:31:49 INFO - Step 0 - I add "LYRASIS Reads" account from welcomeScreen 2023-03-11 17:31:49 INFO - Button 'btnCloseTutorial' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:31:52 INFO - Button 'btnFindLibrary' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:31:52 INFO - Button 'Search' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:31:54 INFO - Text Field 'Search' :: Clearing 2023-03-11 17:31:54 INFO - Text Field 'Search' :: Typing 'LYRASIS Reads' 2023-03-11 17:31:56 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:31:56 INFO - Step 1 - Account 'LYRASIS Reads' is present on Accounts screen 2023-03-11 17:31:56 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:31:57 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:31:58 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:32:00 INFO - Step 2 - I enter credentials for 'LYRASIS Reads' account 2023-03-11 17:32:00 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:32:01 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:32:01 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:32:02 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:32:03 INFO - Locking credential with barcode 01230000000305 2023-03-11 17:32:03 INFO - There are books on the account: 2023-03-11 17:32:04 INFO - There is not books on the account. 2023-03-11 17:32:04 INFO - Count of books on the account after opening account: 0 2023-03-11 17:32:04 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Clearing 2023-03-11 17:32:04 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Typing '01230000000305' 2023-03-11 17:32:06 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Clearing 2023-03-11 17:32:06 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Typing '********' 2023-03-11 17:32:08 INFO - Button 'Log in' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:32:14 INFO - Button 'Log ... action' :: Getting text from element 2023-03-11 17:32:14 INFO - Step 3 - Login is performed successfully 2023-03-11 17:32:35 INFO - Button 'Log ... action' :: Getting text from element 2023-03-11 17:32:35 INFO - Step 4 - I open Catalog 2023-03-11 17:32:35 INFO - Button 'tabCatalog' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:32:56 INFO - Step 5 - I open search modal 2023-03-11 17:33:16 INFO - Button 'Search' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:33:17 INFO - Step 6 - I search 'available' book of distributor 'Palace Marketplace' and bookType 'EBOOK' from "LYRASIS Reads" and save as 'bookNameInfo' 2023-03-11 17:33:17 INFO - Count of attempts to get random book name without bad symbols-1 2023-03-11 17:33:17 INFO - randomBookName: As Good as Gone 2023-03-11 17:33:17 INFO - Error details button is not present 2023-03-11 17:33:17 INFO - Text Field 'Search value input' :: Sending keys 'As Good as Gone' 2023-03-11 17:33:19 INFO - Error details button is not present 2023-03-11 17:33:23 INFO - Step 7 - Click GET action button on EBOOK book with 'bookNameInfo' bookName on catalog books screen and save book as 'bookInfo' 2023-03-11 17:33:24 INFO - Label 'lblAuthor' :: Getting text from element 2023-03-11 17:33:24 INFO - Button 'actionButton' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:33:30 INFO - Step 8 - Open EBOOK book with READ action button and 'bookNameInfo' bookName on catalog books screen and save book as 'bookInfo' 2023-03-11 17:33:31 INFO - Label 'lblAuthor' :: Getting text from element 2023-03-11 17:33:31 INFO - Label 'lblBookName' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:33:31 INFO - Step 9 - Click READ action button on book details screen 2023-03-11 17:33:32 INFO - Button 'Read' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:33:33 INFO - Step 10 - I scroll page forward from 7 to 9 times 2023-03-11 17:33:33 INFO - Scrolling 8 times on reader epub screen 2023-03-11 17:33:51 INFO - Step 11 - I open font settings 2023-03-11 17:33:51 INFO - Button 'btnFontSettings' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:33:52 INFO - Step 12 - I change font style to FONT_SERIF 2023-03-11 17:33:52 INFO - Button 'setFontSerif' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:33:52 INFO - Step 13 - Book text displays in FONT_SERIF font 2023-03-11 17:33:53 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-03-11 17:33:53 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-03-11 17:33:53 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-03-11 17:33:53 INFO -

ONE

He’s watching, Bill Sidey thinks. My father is watching me at this very moment. But Bill can’t take his eyes off the road, a steep, twisting two-track trail that winds down from the top of the butte to the canyon floor.

A juniper bush scratches the side of the car and Bill winces. Something that sounds more solid than weeds scrapes along the undercarriage. But there’s nothing Bill can do other than keep the tires in the ruts and feather the brakes to make sure he doesn’t lose control on his descent.

And sure enough, when the road finally levels off and Bill permits himself a look farther ahead, he sees the figure that he’s sure has been there all along. A tall, lean white-haired man stands in the open doorway of a twenty-foot house trailer, his hands jammed in the pockets of his faded Levi’s. Calvin Sidey, Bill’s father. A hawk with prey in sight could not watch more intently.

Bill parks next to the familiar old Ford truck, yet his father makes no move to come forward. Bill climbs out of the car, and when he slams the door behind him, it sets up an echo that bounces from one canyon wall to the other.

He lives here, Bill thinks, so he can see the enemy approach. It’s the same thought he’s had on the other occasions when he’s driven out to his father’s home, but this time Bill wonders if even he has that status in his father’s eyes.

His father calls out warily, “I didn’t know you were coming.”

To that Bill has no response. His father doesn’t have a telephone. He picks up his mail no more than once or twice a week. How can anyone, son or stranger, notify Calvin Sidey of an impending visit?

His father tries again. “What brings you out this way?”

And that’s Calvin Sidey in a sentence: Let’s get to it. Well, that suits Bill too. When he looks toward his father, Bill has to shield his eyes against the sun glinting off the trailer’s aluminum siding.

“I’ve got a favor to ask.”

His father steps back inside the trailer, but since he doesn’t shut and lock the door behind him, Bill understands that he’s supposed to follow.

The trailer’s interior, even with windows open on every side, must be fifteen degrees hotter than the July afternoon that’s already topped ninety degrees. “Can I get you a cup of coffee?” his father asks.

“Coffee? Jesus. No. A glass of water? Please.”

The trailer is exactly as Bill remembers it, and why not. It’s likely that nothing more than the calendar page has changed since Bill was last here, though he can’t recall when that might have been. His father has his life stripped down to the essentials, and for everything that’s left he has a hook, shelf, bin, drawer, peg, or rack. Bill guesses that in the cupboard there are no more than one or at most two plates, bowls, glasses, and cups. In the same cupboard will be a can of coffee, a box of oatmeal, a few cans of soup and beans, lard, crackers, flour, sugar, salt, and pepper. Above the two burner stove hang a sauce pan and a frying pan. On a shelf above the neatly made bed is a short row of books, and though Bill can’t see the titles, he doesn’t have to. These are his father’s copies of Virgil, Horace, Juvenal, Ovid, Cicero, Catullus, and Pliny. The homemade gun rack above the door holds his Winchester lever-action .30-30, a twelve-gauge Remington pump shotgun, and a fishing pole. And there’s that calendar, hanging right next to the door. It’s this year’s and the page is turned to the correct month, but Bill wonders if his father knows the date. Even if he does, the day surely doesn’t mean “holiday” to him the way it does for most Americans, though it’s hard to imagine a man who values independence more than Calvin Sidey.

Bill stands by the small kitchen table, but since his father has not invited him to sit down, Bill doesn’t pull out one of the two chairs. And why two, Bill wonders, since his father lives alone and never has guests.

From a pitcher on the counter Calvin Sidey pours water into a glass, then sets the glass on the table next to an open book. Bill can’t decipher any of the words on the page because the book is in Latin, a subject Bill never studied in school but which his father has never stopped studying and translating. Also on the table is an ashtray containing a few butts of hand-rolled cigarettes.

Bill brings the glass to his lips and drinks. The water isn’t very cold and it has a brassy odor.

“Why don’t you move this trailer, Dad? That stand of cottonwoods can’t be more than fifty yards away, and if you were parked over there, you’d have some shade.”

His father crosses his arms. “You said you had a favor to ask.”

Bill is sweating in these close quarters, and he loosens his tie and collar. “Marjorie needs an operation.”

“Uh-huh.”

“She has to have a hysterectomy. It’s an operation to—”

“I know what a hysterectomy is. What I don’t know is why you felt you had to come out here and tell me about it in person. How serious is this?”

“She has . . . not tumors, exactly. But growths, painful growths.”

“All right,” his father says. “I’m sorry to hear this. But you drove all the way out here . . . What’s the favor you need?”

“Do you mind if I sit down?” Bill asks, then pulls out a chair before his father can answer.

There’s an odor in the trailer that Bill can’t quite place, a smell reminiscent of gasoline or fresh paint. He looks around to see if his father has recently painted or varnished something. Then it comes to him. Kerosene. Lacking electricity, his father relies on candles or kerosene lamps. It’s 1963, but in many ways his father is living in the nineteenth century. Of course it’s stifling inside the trailer, Bill thinks. His father doesn’t even have a fan to stir the heat or a refrigerator to keep food cold. And not far from the trailer is an outhouse . . .

“There’s a doctor in Missoula who’ll perform the operation,” Bill says. “Carole—you remember Marjorie’s sister?—had the same condition as Marjorie. Same symptoms. Same tests. Apparently it’s something that runs in the family. And Carole had the surgery. Before then, she’d tried everything, and she says if it wasn’t for the operation, she’d still be suffering.”

“Most women would just bite down hard and wait for the misery to pass. Which it will.”

“Most women?”

“In my experience.”

“Something of an expert, are you, Dad?”

His father ignores this question. “Marjorie has to go to Missoula? I know Gladstone’s got doctors who can perform a hysterectomy.”

Bill has to smile. His father is still loyal to Gladstone, though he turned his back on the town almost thirty years ago.

“How about Mitch McCoy?” his father says. “Last I heard he was still practicing.”

“The last you heard? When was that? Dr. McCoy is in a nursing home in Miles City.”

“Mitchell McCoy? Are you sure?”

The heat, the long drive, his father’s questions . . . Bill Sidey suddenly feels tired. He leans on his hand and rubs his eyes. “Yeah, Dad. I’m sure. Look, I can’t pretend to explain it very well. Apparently the Missoula doctor has a special procedure. He doesn’t take out the entire womb or something. The point is, Marjorie wants the operation. She needs the operation.”

“And I reckon you’re all set for her to have what she needs.”

“We’re leaving in a few days.”

“Uh-huh.”

Bill inhales deeply and then exhales, but the heat seems to prevent his breath from traveling far. “That’s what I wanted to ask you about, Dad. Would you be willing to stay with the kids while Marjorie and I are in Missoula?”

His father involuntarily takes a step back. “Have you spoken to your sister about this?”

“Jeanette and I have sort of lost touch. I assume she’s still in New Hampshire. We send the Christmas and birthday cards there and they don’t come back undeliverable. Of course, we don’t get any acknowledgment from her either. How about you?” Bill asks, though he’s certain of the answer. “Do you hear from her?”

His father gives a quick shake of his head.

“What I’m asking you for,” says Bill, “wouldn’t be more than a week. At most.”

“You’re traveling in a few days, you say?”

He’s trying to find a way to say no, Bill thinks. He’s out of practice, and he can’t find a reason quick enough. Why doesn’t he come right out and say it—they’re not my kids or my responsibility. He could say it when the children were his own, so what’s stopping him now? Suddenly, Bill, who all his life has felt diminished in this man’s presence, feels an odd surge of power.

“Ann and Will,” says Bill. “In case you’re trying to recall their names. Ann’s seventeen and Will’s eleven.”

“I know my grandchildren’s names.”

“Ann’s working at J. C. Penney this summer,” Bill continues. “That’s why I’m asking you for this favor. Ordinarily Ann could take care of her brother. And take care of the house. But with the hours she’s working, Will would be alone too much of the day.”

From out of his shirt pocket, his father takes a packet of cigarette papers, and when he looks around for his tin of Sir Walter Raleigh, Bill hurries to offer his father one of his own Camels. The men light their cigarettes, and while this action has given his father an extra minute to think, it’s less time than he would have had rolling his own.

“Have you been working, Dad?” There, Bill thinks, he has opened a door through which his father can escape. He can simply excuse himself by saying he has the obligations of a job.

“Not since last fall,” his father says. “I helped George Tell move his herd down from summer pasture. I’m sure he moved them back up last month, but I didn’t hear from him. Before that? I don’t recall.”

“We could hire a babysitter,” Bill says. “A college girl home for the summer perhaps. Though that might embarrass Ann, someone there so close to her age. Or maybe we could find a farm girl. But you know the house, Dad. And the business. And you’re—”

Bill isn’t sure why he suddenly stops short of uttering the word, especially since it’s the word that he came here to say to his father.

“I’m what?”

“Family,” says Bill, relieved that the word didn’t snag on the way out.

His father draws deep on the Camel, lets the smoke drift from his nostrils, then examines the cigarette as if he’s never smoked a tailor-made before. “When did you say you’re leaving?” he says.

“Sunday. Right after church. And Dad? I’m not asking you to do anything with the kids. Just to be there. Just in case.”

His father walks to the trailer door, opens it, and flicks his cigarette outside. “I’ll be there Saturday,” he says.

His father remains in the doorway, his hand on the handle of the screen door. Just as Bill understood earlier that he was supposed to follow his father inside the trailer, now he understands that he’s expected to leave. “I’ll look for you then,” Bill says.

He steps out into the shadowless sunlight, and though the air’s not moving outside the trailer any more than it was inside—it’s the rare calm day in this part of Montana—Bill feels as though his first breath outdoors goes right to the bottom of his lungs.

“And Bill,” his father calls after him. “Don’t put anyone out of their room. I’ll fix up a little space in the basement.”

“The basement? Dad . . .”

“It’ll be cooler down there.”

Cooler? Bill thinks but doesn’t say. Yet you live here?

“And it’ll give me some privacy,” his father adds.

Privacy for what? Bill thinks. “Whatever you say, Dad. I’ll see you Saturday.”

FROM INSIDE THE TRAILER, Calvin watches his son drive away. He wonders why he said yes to his son’s request, which, he can’t help noting, was offered without a please and accepted without a thank-you. Hadn’t he banished long ago any feelings of obligation to others? Did he say yes simply because of blood? Could he have said no to anyone but his son? Or is this solitary life less endurable than he believes? Maybe he would have listened to any request that tried to bring him back inside the human circle. Well, no point in speculating. He said yes.

The car is out of sight now, but he can hear it, the engine laboring hard as it tries to crest the butte. Shift down, God damn it, Calvin thinks. Though Bill has climbed plenty of hills without his father’s help.

Calvin walks back to the table. He stands over the book he’d been reading earlier. He flips pages until he comes to a poem he knows well. The words are in Latin, but in English he recites softly, “Now he is treading that dark road to the place from which they say no one has ever returned.” Calvin has to smile to himself. Such portentous lines for a bird.

2023-03-11 17:33:53 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-03-11 17:33:54 INFO - Step 14 - I restart app 2023-03-11 17:34:18 INFO - Step 15 - I open Books 2023-03-11 17:34:18 INFO - Button 'tabBooks' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:34:18 INFO - Step 16 - Open EBOOK book with READ action button and 'bookInfo' bookInfo on books screen 2023-03-11 17:34:19 INFO - Label 'lblBookName' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:34:20 INFO - Step 17 - Click READ action button on book details screen 2023-03-11 17:34:21 INFO - Button 'Read' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:34:21 INFO - Step 18 - Book text displays in FONT_SERIF font 2023-03-11 17:34:21 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-03-11 17:34:21 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-03-11 17:34:23 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-03-11 17:34:23 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-03-11 17:34:23 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-03-11 17:34:24 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-03-11 17:34:24 INFO -

ONE

He’s watching, Bill Sidey thinks. My father is watching me at this very moment. But Bill can’t take his eyes off the road, a steep, twisting two-track trail that winds down from the top of the butte to the canyon floor.

A juniper bush scratches the side of the car and Bill winces. Something that sounds more solid than weeds scrapes along the undercarriage. But there’s nothing Bill can do other than keep the tires in the ruts and feather the brakes to make sure he doesn’t lose control on his descent.

And sure enough, when the road finally levels off and Bill permits himself a look farther ahead, he sees the figure that he’s sure has been there all along. A tall, lean white-haired man stands in the open doorway of a twenty-foot house trailer, his hands jammed in the pockets of his faded Levi’s. Calvin Sidey, Bill’s father. A hawk with prey in sight could not watch more intently.

Bill parks next to the familiar old Ford truck, yet his father makes no move to come forward. Bill climbs out of the car, and when he slams the door behind him, it sets up an echo that bounces from one canyon wall to the other.

He lives here, Bill thinks, so he can see the enemy approach. It’s the same thought he’s had on the other occasions when he’s driven out to his father’s home, but this time Bill wonders if even he has that status in his father’s eyes.

His father calls out warily, “I didn’t know you were coming.”

To that Bill has no response. His father doesn’t have a telephone. He picks up his mail no more than once or twice a week. How can anyone, son or stranger, notify Calvin Sidey of an impending visit?

His father tries again. “What brings you out this way?”

And that’s Calvin Sidey in a sentence: Let’s get to it. Well, that suits Bill too. When he looks toward his father, Bill has to shield his eyes against the sun glinting off the trailer’s aluminum siding.

“I’ve got a favor to ask.”

His father steps back inside the trailer, but since he doesn’t shut and lock the door behind him, Bill understands that he’s supposed to follow.

The trailer’s interior, even with windows open on every side, must be fifteen degrees hotter than the July afternoon that’s already topped ninety degrees. “Can I get you a cup of coffee?” his father asks.

“Coffee? Jesus. No. A glass of water? Please.”

The trailer is exactly as Bill remembers it, and why not. It’s likely that nothing more than the calendar page has changed since Bill was last here, though he can’t recall when that might have been. His father has his life stripped down to the essentials, and for everything that’s left he has a hook, shelf, bin, drawer, peg, or rack. Bill guesses that in the cupboard there are no more than one or at most two plates, bowls, glasses, and cups. In the same cupboard will be a can of coffee, a box of oatmeal, a few cans of soup and beans, lard, crackers, flour, sugar, salt, and pepper. Above the two burner stove hang a sauce pan and a frying pan. On a shelf above the neatly made bed is a short row of books, and though Bill can’t see the titles, he doesn’t have to. These are his father’s copies of Virgil, Horace, Juvenal, Ovid, Cicero, Catullus, and Pliny. The homemade gun rack above the door holds his Winchester lever-action .30-30, a twelve-gauge Remington pump shotgun, and a fishing pole. And there’s that calendar, hanging right next to the door. It’s this year’s and the page is turned to the correct month, but Bill wonders if his father knows the date. Even if he does, the day surely doesn’t mean “holiday” to him the way it does for most Americans, though it’s hard to imagine a man who values independence more than Calvin Sidey.

Bill stands by the small kitchen table, but since his father has not invited him to sit down, Bill doesn’t pull out one of the two chairs. And why two, Bill wonders, since his father lives alone and never has guests.

From a pitcher on the counter Calvin Sidey pours water into a glass, then sets the glass on the table next to an open book. Bill can’t decipher any of the words on the page because the book is in Latin, a subject Bill never studied in school but which his father has never stopped studying and translating. Also on the table is an ashtray containing a few butts of hand-rolled cigarettes.

Bill brings the glass to his lips and drinks. The water isn’t very cold and it has a brassy odor.

“Why don’t you move this trailer, Dad? That stand of cottonwoods can’t be more than fifty yards away, and if you were parked over there, you’d have some shade.”

His father crosses his arms. “You said you had a favor to ask.”

Bill is sweating in these close quarters, and he loosens his tie and collar. “Marjorie needs an operation.”

“Uh-huh.”

“She has to have a hysterectomy. It’s an operation to—”

“I know what a hysterectomy is. What I don’t know is why you felt you had to come out here and tell me about it in person. How serious is this?”

“She has . . . not tumors, exactly. But growths, painful growths.”

“All right,” his father says. “I’m sorry to hear this. But you drove all the way out here . . . What’s the favor you need?”

“Do you mind if I sit down?” Bill asks, then pulls out a chair before his father can answer.

There’s an odor in the trailer that Bill can’t quite place, a smell reminiscent of gasoline or fresh paint. He looks around to see if his father has recently painted or varnished something. Then it comes to him. Kerosene. Lacking electricity, his father relies on candles or kerosene lamps. It’s 1963, but in many ways his father is living in the nineteenth century. Of course it’s stifling inside the trailer, Bill thinks. His father doesn’t even have a fan to stir the heat or a refrigerator to keep food cold. And not far from the trailer is an outhouse . . .

“There’s a doctor in Missoula who’ll perform the operation,” Bill says. “Carole—you remember Marjorie’s sister?—had the same condition as Marjorie. Same symptoms. Same tests. Apparently it’s something that runs in the family. And Carole had the surgery. Before then, she’d tried everything, and she says if it wasn’t for the operation, she’d still be suffering.”

“Most women would just bite down hard and wait for the misery to pass. Which it will.”

“Most women?”

“In my experience.”

“Something of an expert, are you, Dad?”

His father ignores this question. “Marjorie has to go to Missoula? I know Gladstone’s got doctors who can perform a hysterectomy.”

Bill has to smile. His father is still loyal to Gladstone, though he turned his back on the town almost thirty years ago.

“How about Mitch McCoy?” his father says. “Last I heard he was still practicing.”

“The last you heard? When was that? Dr. McCoy is in a nursing home in Miles City.”

“Mitchell McCoy? Are you sure?”

The heat, the long drive, his father’s questions . . . Bill Sidey suddenly feels tired. He leans on his hand and rubs his eyes. “Yeah, Dad. I’m sure. Look, I can’t pretend to explain it very well. Apparently the Missoula doctor has a special procedure. He doesn’t take out the entire womb or something. The point is, Marjorie wants the operation. She needs the operation.”

“And I reckon you’re all set for her to have what she needs.”

“We’re leaving in a few days.”

“Uh-huh.”

Bill inhales deeply and then exhales, but the heat seems to prevent his breath from traveling far. “That’s what I wanted to ask you about, Dad. Would you be willing to stay with the kids while Marjorie and I are in Missoula?”

His father involuntarily takes a step back. “Have you spoken to your sister about this?”

“Jeanette and I have sort of lost touch. I assume she’s still in New Hampshire. We send the Christmas and birthday cards there and they don’t come back undeliverable. Of course, we don’t get any acknowledgment from her either. How about you?” Bill asks, though he’s certain of the answer. “Do you hear from her?”

His father gives a quick shake of his head.

“What I’m asking you for,” says Bill, “wouldn’t be more than a week. At most.”

“You’re traveling in a few days, you say?”

He’s trying to find a way to say no, Bill thinks. He’s out of practice, and he can’t find a reason quick enough. Why doesn’t he come right out and say it—they’re not my kids or my responsibility. He could say it when the children were his own, so what’s stopping him now? Suddenly, Bill, who all his life has felt diminished in this man’s presence, feels an odd surge of power.

“Ann and Will,” says Bill. “In case you’re trying to recall their names. Ann’s seventeen and Will’s eleven.”

“I know my grandchildren’s names.”

“Ann’s working at J. C. Penney this summer,” Bill continues. “That’s why I’m asking you for this favor. Ordinarily Ann could take care of her brother. And take care of the house. But with the hours she’s working, Will would be alone too much of the day.”

From out of his shirt pocket, his father takes a packet of cigarette papers, and when he looks around for his tin of Sir Walter Raleigh, Bill hurries to offer his father one of his own Camels. The men light their cigarettes, and while this action has given his father an extra minute to think, it’s less time than he would have had rolling his own.

“Have you been working, Dad?” There, Bill thinks, he has opened a door through which his father can escape. He can simply excuse himself by saying he has the obligations of a job.

“Not since last fall,” his father says. “I helped George Tell move his herd down from summer pasture. I’m sure he moved them back up last month, but I didn’t hear from him. Before that? I don’t recall.”

“We could hire a babysitter,” Bill says. “A college girl home for the summer perhaps. Though that might embarrass Ann, someone there so close to her age. Or maybe we could find a farm girl. But you know the house, Dad. And the business. And you’re—”

Bill isn’t sure why he suddenly stops short of uttering the word, especially since it’s the word that he came here to say to his father.

“I’m what?”

“Family,” says Bill, relieved that the word didn’t snag on the way out.

His father draws deep on the Camel, lets the smoke drift from his nostrils, then examines the cigarette as if he’s never smoked a tailor-made before. “When did you say you’re leaving?” he says.

“Sunday. Right after church. And Dad? I’m not asking you to do anything with the kids. Just to be there. Just in case.”

His father walks to the trailer door, opens it, and flicks his cigarette outside. “I’ll be there Saturday,” he says.

His father remains in the doorway, his hand on the handle of the screen door. Just as Bill understood earlier that he was supposed to follow his father inside the trailer, now he understands that he’s expected to leave. “I’ll look for you then,” Bill says.

He steps out into the shadowless sunlight, and though the air’s not moving outside the trailer any more than it was inside—it’s the rare calm day in this part of Montana—Bill feels as though his first breath outdoors goes right to the bottom of his lungs.

“And Bill,” his father calls after him. “Don’t put anyone out of their room. I’ll fix up a little space in the basement.”

“The basement? Dad . . .”

“It’ll be cooler down there.”

Cooler? Bill thinks but doesn’t say. Yet you live here?

“And it’ll give me some privacy,” his father adds.

Privacy for what? Bill thinks. “Whatever you say, Dad. I’ll see you Saturday.”

FROM INSIDE THE TRAILER, Calvin watches his son drive away. He wonders why he said yes to his son’s request, which, he can’t help noting, was offered without a please and accepted without a thank-you. Hadn’t he banished long ago any feelings of obligation to others? Did he say yes simply because of blood? Could he have said no to anyone but his son? Or is this solitary life less endurable than he believes? Maybe he would have listened to any request that tried to bring him back inside the human circle. Well, no point in speculating. He said yes.

The car is out of sight now, but he can hear it, the engine laboring hard as it tries to crest the butte. Shift down, God damn it, Calvin thinks. Though Bill has climbed plenty of hills without his father’s help.

Calvin walks back to the table. He stands over the book he’d been reading earlier. He flips pages until he comes to a poem he knows well. The words are in Latin, but in English he recites softly, “Now he is treading that dark road to the place from which they say no one has ever returned.” Calvin has to smile to himself. Such portentous lines for a bird.

2023-03-11 17:34:24 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-03-11 17:34:24 INFO - Step 19 - I return to previous screen from epub 2023-03-11 17:34:25 INFO - Button 'btnBack' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:34:25 INFO - Step 20 - Click READ action button on book details screen 2023-03-11 17:34:26 INFO - Button 'Read' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:34:26 INFO - Step 21 - Book text displays in FONT_SERIF font 2023-03-11 17:34:27 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-03-11 17:34:27 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-03-11 17:34:28 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-03-11 17:34:28 INFO -

ONE

He’s watching, Bill Sidey thinks. My father is watching me at this very moment. But Bill can’t take his eyes off the road, a steep, twisting two-track trail that winds down from the top of the butte to the canyon floor.

A juniper bush scratches the side of the car and Bill winces. Something that sounds more solid than weeds scrapes along the undercarriage. But there’s nothing Bill can do other than keep the tires in the ruts and feather the brakes to make sure he doesn’t lose control on his descent.

And sure enough, when the road finally levels off and Bill permits himself a look farther ahead, he sees the figure that he’s sure has been there all along. A tall, lean white-haired man stands in the open doorway of a twenty-foot house trailer, his hands jammed in the pockets of his faded Levi’s. Calvin Sidey, Bill’s father. A hawk with prey in sight could not watch more intently.

Bill parks next to the familiar old Ford truck, yet his father makes no move to come forward. Bill climbs out of the car, and when he slams the door behind him, it sets up an echo that bounces from one canyon wall to the other.

He lives here, Bill thinks, so he can see the enemy approach. It’s the same thought he’s had on the other occasions when he’s driven out to his father’s home, but this time Bill wonders if even he has that status in his father’s eyes.

His father calls out warily, “I didn’t know you were coming.”

To that Bill has no response. His father doesn’t have a telephone. He picks up his mail no more than once or twice a week. How can anyone, son or stranger, notify Calvin Sidey of an impending visit?

His father tries again. “What brings you out this way?”

And that’s Calvin Sidey in a sentence: Let’s get to it. Well, that suits Bill too. When he looks toward his father, Bill has to shield his eyes against the sun glinting off the trailer’s aluminum siding.

“I’ve got a favor to ask.”

His father steps back inside the trailer, but since he doesn’t shut and lock the door behind him, Bill understands that he’s supposed to follow.

The trailer’s interior, even with windows open on every side, must be fifteen degrees hotter than the July afternoon that’s already topped ninety degrees. “Can I get you a cup of coffee?” his father asks.

“Coffee? Jesus. No. A glass of water? Please.”

The trailer is exactly as Bill remembers it, and why not. It’s likely that nothing more than the calendar page has changed since Bill was last here, though he can’t recall when that might have been. His father has his life stripped down to the essentials, and for everything that’s left he has a hook, shelf, bin, drawer, peg, or rack. Bill guesses that in the cupboard there are no more than one or at most two plates, bowls, glasses, and cups. In the same cupboard will be a can of coffee, a box of oatmeal, a few cans of soup and beans, lard, crackers, flour, sugar, salt, and pepper. Above the two burner stove hang a sauce pan and a frying pan. On a shelf above the neatly made bed is a short row of books, and though Bill can’t see the titles, he doesn’t have to. These are his father’s copies of Virgil, Horace, Juvenal, Ovid, Cicero, Catullus, and Pliny. The homemade gun rack above the door holds his Winchester lever-action .30-30, a twelve-gauge Remington pump shotgun, and a fishing pole. And there’s that calendar, hanging right next to the door. It’s this year’s and the page is turned to the correct month, but Bill wonders if his father knows the date. Even if he does, the day surely doesn’t mean “holiday” to him the way it does for most Americans, though it’s hard to imagine a man who values independence more than Calvin Sidey.

Bill stands by the small kitchen table, but since his father has not invited him to sit down, Bill doesn’t pull out one of the two chairs. And why two, Bill wonders, since his father lives alone and never has guests.

From a pitcher on the counter Calvin Sidey pours water into a glass, then sets the glass on the table next to an open book. Bill can’t decipher any of the words on the page because the book is in Latin, a subject Bill never studied in school but which his father has never stopped studying and translating. Also on the table is an ashtray containing a few butts of hand-rolled cigarettes.

Bill brings the glass to his lips and drinks. The water isn’t very cold and it has a brassy odor.

“Why don’t you move this trailer, Dad? That stand of cottonwoods can’t be more than fifty yards away, and if you were parked over there, you’d have some shade.”

His father crosses his arms. “You said you had a favor to ask.”

Bill is sweating in these close quarters, and he loosens his tie and collar. “Marjorie needs an operation.”

“Uh-huh.”

“She has to have a hysterectomy. It’s an operation to—”

“I know what a hysterectomy is. What I don’t know is why you felt you had to come out here and tell me about it in person. How serious is this?”

“She has . . . not tumors, exactly. But growths, painful growths.”

“All right,” his father says. “I’m sorry to hear this. But you drove all the way out here . . . What’s the favor you need?”

“Do you mind if I sit down?” Bill asks, then pulls out a chair before his father can answer.

There’s an odor in the trailer that Bill can’t quite place, a smell reminiscent of gasoline or fresh paint. He looks around to see if his father has recently painted or varnished something. Then it comes to him. Kerosene. Lacking electricity, his father relies on candles or kerosene lamps. It’s 1963, but in many ways his father is living in the nineteenth century. Of course it’s stifling inside the trailer, Bill thinks. His father doesn’t even have a fan to stir the heat or a refrigerator to keep food cold. And not far from the trailer is an outhouse . . .

“There’s a doctor in Missoula who’ll perform the operation,” Bill says. “Carole—you remember Marjorie’s sister?—had the same condition as Marjorie. Same symptoms. Same tests. Apparently it’s something that runs in the family. And Carole had the surgery. Before then, she’d tried everything, and she says if it wasn’t for the operation, she’d still be suffering.”

“Most women would just bite down hard and wait for the misery to pass. Which it will.”

“Most women?”

“In my experience.”

“Something of an expert, are you, Dad?”

His father ignores this question. “Marjorie has to go to Missoula? I know Gladstone’s got doctors who can perform a hysterectomy.”

Bill has to smile. His father is still loyal to Gladstone, though he turned his back on the town almost thirty years ago.

“How about Mitch McCoy?” his father says. “Last I heard he was still practicing.”

“The last you heard? When was that? Dr. McCoy is in a nursing home in Miles City.”

“Mitchell McCoy? Are you sure?”

The heat, the long drive, his father’s questions . . . Bill Sidey suddenly feels tired. He leans on his hand and rubs his eyes. “Yeah, Dad. I’m sure. Look, I can’t pretend to explain it very well. Apparently the Missoula doctor has a special procedure. He doesn’t take out the entire womb or something. The point is, Marjorie wants the operation. She needs the operation.”

“And I reckon you’re all set for her to have what she needs.”

“We’re leaving in a few days.”

“Uh-huh.”

Bill inhales deeply and then exhales, but the heat seems to prevent his breath from traveling far. “That’s what I wanted to ask you about, Dad. Would you be willing to stay with the kids while Marjorie and I are in Missoula?”

His father involuntarily takes a step back. “Have you spoken to your sister about this?”

“Jeanette and I have sort of lost touch. I assume she’s still in New Hampshire. We send the Christmas and birthday cards there and they don’t come back undeliverable. Of course, we don’t get any acknowledgment from her either. How about you?” Bill asks, though he’s certain of the answer. “Do you hear from her?”

His father gives a quick shake of his head.

“What I’m asking you for,” says Bill, “wouldn’t be more than a week. At most.”

“You’re traveling in a few days, you say?”

He’s trying to find a way to say no, Bill thinks. He’s out of practice, and he can’t find a reason quick enough. Why doesn’t he come right out and say it—they’re not my kids or my responsibility. He could say it when the children were his own, so what’s stopping him now? Suddenly, Bill, who all his life has felt diminished in this man’s presence, feels an odd surge of power.

“Ann and Will,” says Bill. “In case you’re trying to recall their names. Ann’s seventeen and Will’s eleven.”

“I know my grandchildren’s names.”

“Ann’s working at J. C. Penney this summer,” Bill continues. “That’s why I’m asking you for this favor. Ordinarily Ann could take care of her brother. And take care of the house. But with the hours she’s working, Will would be alone too much of the day.”

From out of his shirt pocket, his father takes a packet of cigarette papers, and when he looks around for his tin of Sir Walter Raleigh, Bill hurries to offer his father one of his own Camels. The men light their cigarettes, and while this action has given his father an extra minute to think, it’s less time than he would have had rolling his own.

“Have you been working, Dad?” There, Bill thinks, he has opened a door through which his father can escape. He can simply excuse himself by saying he has the obligations of a job.

“Not since last fall,” his father says. “I helped George Tell move his herd down from summer pasture. I’m sure he moved them back up last month, but I didn’t hear from him. Before that? I don’t recall.”

“We could hire a babysitter,” Bill says. “A college girl home for the summer perhaps. Though that might embarrass Ann, someone there so close to her age. Or maybe we could find a farm girl. But you know the house, Dad. And the business. And you’re—”

Bill isn’t sure why he suddenly stops short of uttering the word, especially since it’s the word that he came here to say to his father.

“I’m what?”

“Family,” says Bill, relieved that the word didn’t snag on the way out.

His father draws deep on the Camel, lets the smoke drift from his nostrils, then examines the cigarette as if he’s never smoked a tailor-made before. “When did you say you’re leaving?” he says.

“Sunday. Right after church. And Dad? I’m not asking you to do anything with the kids. Just to be there. Just in case.”

His father walks to the trailer door, opens it, and flicks his cigarette outside. “I’ll be there Saturday,” he says.

His father remains in the doorway, his hand on the handle of the screen door. Just as Bill understood earlier that he was supposed to follow his father inside the trailer, now he understands that he’s expected to leave. “I’ll look for you then,” Bill says.

He steps out into the shadowless sunlight, and though the air’s not moving outside the trailer any more than it was inside—it’s the rare calm day in this part of Montana—Bill feels as though his first breath outdoors goes right to the bottom of his lungs.

“And Bill,” his father calls after him. “Don’t put anyone out of their room. I’ll fix up a little space in the basement.”

“The basement? Dad . . .”

“It’ll be cooler down there.”

Cooler? Bill thinks but doesn’t say. Yet you live here?

“And it’ll give me some privacy,” his father adds.

Privacy for what? Bill thinks. “Whatever you say, Dad. I’ll see you Saturday.”

FROM INSIDE THE TRAILER, Calvin watches his son drive away. He wonders why he said yes to his son’s request, which, he can’t help noting, was offered without a please and accepted without a thank-you. Hadn’t he banished long ago any feelings of obligation to others? Did he say yes simply because of blood? Could he have said no to anyone but his son? Or is this solitary life less endurable than he believes? Maybe he would have listened to any request that tried to bring him back inside the human circle. Well, no point in speculating. He said yes.

The car is out of sight now, but he can hear it, the engine laboring hard as it tries to crest the butte. Shift down, God damn it, Calvin thinks. Though Bill has climbed plenty of hills without his father’s help.

Calvin walks back to the table. He stands over the book he’d been reading earlier. He flips pages until he comes to a poem he knows well. The words are in Latin, but in English he recites softly, “Now he is treading that dark road to the place from which they say no one has ever returned.” Calvin has to smile to himself. Such portentous lines for a bird.

2023-03-11 17:34:28 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-03-11 17:34:28 INFO - Step 22 - I open font settings 2023-03-11 17:34:30 INFO - Button 'btnFontSettings' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:34:30 INFO - Step 23 - I change font style to FONT_SANS 2023-03-11 17:34:30 INFO - Button 'setFontSans' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:34:31 INFO - Step 24 - Book text displays in FONT_SANS font 2023-03-11 17:34:31 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-03-11 17:34:31 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-03-11 17:34:31 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-03-11 17:34:31 INFO -

ONE

He’s watching, Bill Sidey thinks. My father is watching me at this very moment. But Bill can’t take his eyes off the road, a steep, twisting two-track trail that winds down from the top of the butte to the canyon floor.

A juniper bush scratches the side of the car and Bill winces. Something that sounds more solid than weeds scrapes along the undercarriage. But there’s nothing Bill can do other than keep the tires in the ruts and feather the brakes to make sure he doesn’t lose control on his descent.

And sure enough, when the road finally levels off and Bill permits himself a look farther ahead, he sees the figure that he’s sure has been there all along. A tall, lean white-haired man stands in the open doorway of a twenty-foot house trailer, his hands jammed in the pockets of his faded Levi’s. Calvin Sidey, Bill’s father. A hawk with prey in sight could not watch more intently.

Bill parks next to the familiar old Ford truck, yet his father makes no move to come forward. Bill climbs out of the car, and when he slams the door behind him, it sets up an echo that bounces from one canyon wall to the other.

He lives here, Bill thinks, so he can see the enemy approach. It’s the same thought he’s had on the other occasions when he’s driven out to his father’s home, but this time Bill wonders if even he has that status in his father’s eyes.

His father calls out warily, “I didn’t know you were coming.”

To that Bill has no response. His father doesn’t have a telephone. He picks up his mail no more than once or twice a week. How can anyone, son or stranger, notify Calvin Sidey of an impending visit?

His father tries again. “What brings you out this way?”

And that’s Calvin Sidey in a sentence: Let’s get to it. Well, that suits Bill too. When he looks toward his father, Bill has to shield his eyes against the sun glinting off the trailer’s aluminum siding.

“I’ve got a favor to ask.”

His father steps back inside the trailer, but since he doesn’t shut and lock the door behind him, Bill understands that he’s supposed to follow.

The trailer’s interior, even with windows open on every side, must be fifteen degrees hotter than the July afternoon that’s already topped ninety degrees. “Can I get you a cup of coffee?” his father asks.

“Coffee? Jesus. No. A glass of water? Please.”

The trailer is exactly as Bill remembers it, and why not. It’s likely that nothing more than the calendar page has changed since Bill was last here, though he can’t recall when that might have been. His father has his life stripped down to the essentials, and for everything that’s left he has a hook, shelf, bin, drawer, peg, or rack. Bill guesses that in the cupboard there are no more than one or at most two plates, bowls, glasses, and cups. In the same cupboard will be a can of coffee, a box of oatmeal, a few cans of soup and beans, lard, crackers, flour, sugar, salt, and pepper. Above the two burner stove hang a sauce pan and a frying pan. On a shelf above the neatly made bed is a short row of books, and though Bill can’t see the titles, he doesn’t have to. These are his father’s copies of Virgil, Horace, Juvenal, Ovid, Cicero, Catullus, and Pliny. The homemade gun rack above the door holds his Winchester lever-action .30-30, a twelve-gauge Remington pump shotgun, and a fishing pole. And there’s that calendar, hanging right next to the door. It’s this year’s and the page is turned to the correct month, but Bill wonders if his father knows the date. Even if he does, the day surely doesn’t mean “holiday” to him the way it does for most Americans, though it’s hard to imagine a man who values independence more than Calvin Sidey.

Bill stands by the small kitchen table, but since his father has not invited him to sit down, Bill doesn’t pull out one of the two chairs. And why two, Bill wonders, since his father lives alone and never has guests.

From a pitcher on the counter Calvin Sidey pours water into a glass, then sets the glass on the table next to an open book. Bill can’t decipher any of the words on the page because the book is in Latin, a subject Bill never studied in school but which his father has never stopped studying and translating. Also on the table is an ashtray containing a few butts of hand-rolled cigarettes.

Bill brings the glass to his lips and drinks. The water isn’t very cold and it has a brassy odor.

“Why don’t you move this trailer, Dad? That stand of cottonwoods can’t be more than fifty yards away, and if you were parked over there, you’d have some shade.”

His father crosses his arms. “You said you had a favor to ask.”

Bill is sweating in these close quarters, and he loosens his tie and collar. “Marjorie needs an operation.”

“Uh-huh.”

“She has to have a hysterectomy. It’s an operation to—”

“I know what a hysterectomy is. What I don’t know is why you felt you had to come out here and tell me about it in person. How serious is this?”

“She has . . . not tumors, exactly. But growths, painful growths.”

“All right,” his father says. “I’m sorry to hear this. But you drove all the way out here . . . What’s the favor you need?”

“Do you mind if I sit down?” Bill asks, then pulls out a chair before his father can answer.

There’s an odor in the trailer that Bill can’t quite place, a smell reminiscent of gasoline or fresh paint. He looks around to see if his father has recently painted or varnished something. Then it comes to him. Kerosene. Lacking electricity, his father relies on candles or kerosene lamps. It’s 1963, but in many ways his father is living in the nineteenth century. Of course it’s stifling inside the trailer, Bill thinks. His father doesn’t even have a fan to stir the heat or a refrigerator to keep food cold. And not far from the trailer is an outhouse . . .

“There’s a doctor in Missoula who’ll perform the operation,” Bill says. “Carole—you remember Marjorie’s sister?—had the same condition as Marjorie. Same symptoms. Same tests. Apparently it’s something that runs in the family. And Carole had the surgery. Before then, she’d tried everything, and she says if it wasn’t for the operation, she’d still be suffering.”

“Most women would just bite down hard and wait for the misery to pass. Which it will.”

“Most women?”

“In my experience.”

“Something of an expert, are you, Dad?”

His father ignores this question. “Marjorie has to go to Missoula? I know Gladstone’s got doctors who can perform a hysterectomy.”

Bill has to smile. His father is still loyal to Gladstone, though he turned his back on the town almost thirty years ago.

“How about Mitch McCoy?” his father says. “Last I heard he was still practicing.”

“The last you heard? When was that? Dr. McCoy is in a nursing home in Miles City.”

“Mitchell McCoy? Are you sure?”

The heat, the long drive, his father’s questions . . . Bill Sidey suddenly feels tired. He leans on his hand and rubs his eyes. “Yeah, Dad. I’m sure. Look, I can’t pretend to explain it very well. Apparently the Missoula doctor has a special procedure. He doesn’t take out the entire womb or something. The point is, Marjorie wants the operation. She needs the operation.”

“And I reckon you’re all set for her to have what she needs.”

“We’re leaving in a few days.”

“Uh-huh.”

Bill inhales deeply and then exhales, but the heat seems to prevent his breath from traveling far. “That’s what I wanted to ask you about, Dad. Would you be willing to stay with the kids while Marjorie and I are in Missoula?”

His father involuntarily takes a step back. “Have you spoken to your sister about this?”

“Jeanette and I have sort of lost touch. I assume she’s still in New Hampshire. We send the Christmas and birthday cards there and they don’t come back undeliverable. Of course, we don’t get any acknowledgment from her either. How about you?” Bill asks, though he’s certain of the answer. “Do you hear from her?”

His father gives a quick shake of his head.

“What I’m asking you for,” says Bill, “wouldn’t be more than a week. At most.”

“You’re traveling in a few days, you say?”

He’s trying to find a way to say no, Bill thinks. He’s out of practice, and he can’t find a reason quick enough. Why doesn’t he come right out and say it—they’re not my kids or my responsibility. He could say it when the children were his own, so what’s stopping him now? Suddenly, Bill, who all his life has felt diminished in this man’s presence, feels an odd surge of power.

“Ann and Will,” says Bill. “In case you’re trying to recall their names. Ann’s seventeen and Will’s eleven.”

“I know my grandchildren’s names.”

“Ann’s working at J. C. Penney this summer,” Bill continues. “That’s why I’m asking you for this favor. Ordinarily Ann could take care of her brother. And take care of the house. But with the hours she’s working, Will would be alone too much of the day.”

From out of his shirt pocket, his father takes a packet of cigarette papers, and when he looks around for his tin of Sir Walter Raleigh, Bill hurries to offer his father one of his own Camels. The men light their cigarettes, and while this action has given his father an extra minute to think, it’s less time than he would have had rolling his own.

“Have you been working, Dad?” There, Bill thinks, he has opened a door through which his father can escape. He can simply excuse himself by saying he has the obligations of a job.

“Not since last fall,” his father says. “I helped George Tell move his herd down from summer pasture. I’m sure he moved them back up last month, but I didn’t hear from him. Before that? I don’t recall.”

“We could hire a babysitter,” Bill says. “A college girl home for the summer perhaps. Though that might embarrass Ann, someone there so close to her age. Or maybe we could find a farm girl. But you know the house, Dad. And the business. And you’re—”

Bill isn’t sure why he suddenly stops short of uttering the word, especially since it’s the word that he came here to say to his father.

“I’m what?”

“Family,” says Bill, relieved that the word didn’t snag on the way out.

His father draws deep on the Camel, lets the smoke drift from his nostrils, then examines the cigarette as if he’s never smoked a tailor-made before. “When did you say you’re leaving?” he says.

“Sunday. Right after church. And Dad? I’m not asking you to do anything with the kids. Just to be there. Just in case.”

His father walks to the trailer door, opens it, and flicks his cigarette outside. “I’ll be there Saturday,” he says.

His father remains in the doorway, his hand on the handle of the screen door. Just as Bill understood earlier that he was supposed to follow his father inside the trailer, now he understands that he’s expected to leave. “I’ll look for you then,” Bill says.

He steps out into the shadowless sunlight, and though the air’s not moving outside the trailer any more than it was inside—it’s the rare calm day in this part of Montana—Bill feels as though his first breath outdoors goes right to the bottom of his lungs.

“And Bill,” his father calls after him. “Don’t put anyone out of their room. I’ll fix up a little space in the basement.”

“The basement? Dad . . .”

“It’ll be cooler down there.”

Cooler? Bill thinks but doesn’t say. Yet you live here?

“And it’ll give me some privacy,” his father adds.

Privacy for what? Bill thinks. “Whatever you say, Dad. I’ll see you Saturday.”

FROM INSIDE THE TRAILER, Calvin watches his son drive away. He wonders why he said yes to his son’s request, which, he can’t help noting, was offered without a please and accepted without a thank-you. Hadn’t he banished long ago any feelings of obligation to others? Did he say yes simply because of blood? Could he have said no to anyone but his son? Or is this solitary life less endurable than he believes? Maybe he would have listened to any request that tried to bring him back inside the human circle. Well, no point in speculating. He said yes.

The car is out of sight now, but he can hear it, the engine laboring hard as it tries to crest the butte. Shift down, God damn it, Calvin thinks. Though Bill has climbed plenty of hills without his father’s help.

Calvin walks back to the table. He stands over the book he’d been reading earlier. He flips pages until he comes to a poem he knows well. The words are in Latin, but in English he recites softly, “Now he is treading that dark road to the place from which they say no one has ever returned.” Calvin has to smile to himself. Such portentous lines for a bird.

2023-03-11 17:34:31 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-03-11 17:34:32 INFO - Taking screenshot 2023-03-11 17:34:32 INFO - Test finished - logging out 2023-03-11 17:34:33 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:34:36 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:34:37 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:34:38 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:34:39 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Getting text from element 2023-03-11 17:34:40 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Getting text from element 2023-03-11 17:34:40 INFO - Button 'Log out' :: Clicking 2023-03-11 17:34:40 INFO - Button 'Log in' :: Getting text from element 2023-03-11 17:34:44 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Getting text from element 2023-03-11 17:34:44 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Getting text from element 2023-03-11 17:34:44 INFO - Unlocking credential for current thread 2023-03-11 17:34:44 INFO - isLoggerNullAfterAnnotation-framework.utilities.Logger@1dfe12c0